Krish NAik: Yeah, hello everyone, am I audible? Please let me know in the chat. Just check the chats are opened or not.
Krish NAik: Alright, guys.
Krish NAik: So, today… Okay, so we will continue our discussion, something with respect to that advanced track tutorial.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think, let me get my screen.
Krish NAik: Here's better at that, but I will discuss it today.
Krish NAik: I think, alright, few things I am planning… just wait. This is, I think, to stop it.
Krish NAik: BG3 and rank convert it.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so, like, I'll be sharing a Google form with you, okay? The idea is that, for 2.0, like, whatever the suggestions and the things that you can give, okay, please provide a quick feedback.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, what are the additional topics based on that? Okay, and probably the second batch, I will be keeping a lot of LLM and fine-tuning stuff.
Krish NAik: and quantization that I am planning. Okay, so I'll be sharing this link. Okay, everybody, please do check that the Google form is available to everyone.
Krish NAik: No, there was no class on Thursday. That Thursday thing today only I will be discussing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it's just like a feedback, so, like, continuously you can…
Krish NAik: edit, because I think in the settings, I will change…
Krish NAik: Multiple responses, allow response editing, limit to one response, it's not there, alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, so anything that comes to your mind, at least you can keep those topics there.
Krish NAik: Alright, so today's discussion, let's start.
Krish NAik: The track is slowly becoming slowly, but, till now, I think in 2026, 2027, it will be there, but from 2028, probably, like,
Krish NAik: Much more, I feel, that multimodal models can perform, but the main problem is compute.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, first of all, everybody, you can open that, advanced…
Krish NAik: I think correct tutorial somewhere from here, this one, okay? So, here, please take a clone. I have added one more BGM3, multi-vector notebook. This notebook, I have just added it today, okay? So, please try to get the new notebook.
Krish NAik: Currently, no Udemy opens or anything.
Krish NAik: Because right now, the team is focused on that, launch. If you guys…
Krish NAik: have looked into the post of Krishna. Most more project-focused.
Krish NAik: That, thing that is coming. Probably on 19th or 22nd, yesterday I was discussing, okay, so…
Krish NAik: Just remember, I think, let me just tell you in Notion exactly where it is. It is the same repo, there are… there is no change with respect to the repo. So, for example, go to the advanced track, and this is that advanced track tutorial, okay? Just click on this one.
Krish NAik: Whoever is there.
Krish NAik: Does the theme one.
Krish NAik: I'm sharing the notion link.
Krish NAik: Because I know there are no new participants for today.
Krish NAik: Yeah, Janik, if the last class you have not gone through, few things will be related to the last class, but the major focus will be there on this.
Krish NAik: already trained.
Krish NAik: Let me start with today's agenda.
Krish NAik: BG, BGM3 notebook.
Krish NAik: So I think I need to share my iPad screen.
Krish NAik: Alright, so…
Krish NAik: Alright, so first of all, a little bit about, unified modeling concept that came around.
Krish NAik: Unified… Modeling.
Krish NAik: And very specifically, like, BGM3, it is available in Ollama also, completely open source. And then, finally, we will jump into a little bit of text-to-SQL.
Krish NAik: Because your second project, is ready, I'm actually testing the deployments there.
Krish NAik: But, that's why it takes to SQL. So this time,
Krish NAik: For text-to-SQL, I will be using Lama, okay? So, Llama I will go with. But in your project, because once you have the basic idea, little bit with respect to much better infra provides, so we will switch to VANA, okay?
Krish NAik: Ivana.ai.
Krish NAik: That part I have taken.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so I will give you a high-level introduction to VANA with respect to integrations. It's much easier in VANA 2.0 as compared to the legacy version.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this will be, I think, from tomorrow, we'll be starting this, so I think a little bit about text-to-SQL.
Krish NAik: And, for our Postgres database, okay, so the major setup, some custom data with respect to Superbase that I'll be hosting, and through connections that I'll be doing.
Krish NAik: This will be the main thing. So, let's start with, first of all, the M3 part, okay? So, let's start our discussion. So, based on the last class, whatever we have discussed till now, okay? So, let me just get that part.
Krish NAik: I will stop sharing again. Somebody is asking which notebook, the notebook is there, which is the BG, this notebook, BGM3 Multivector.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, this model is freely available in Hugging Face. Also, you can go through Hugging Face. So, there is a paper from 2024,
Krish NAik: And I feel that, the paper is a bit good, because even for open source.
Krish NAik: For learning-based solutions, yes, people do use.
Krish NAik: So, like, the name M3, as you can see, like, M3 Embedding.
Krish NAik: Okay, so M3, because three things are there, one is multilinguality, multifunctionality, and multi-granularity. In simple terms, if I see that, as multiple things comes into the picture, like BM25, then you have,
Krish NAik: your, sparse learned vectors. I think everybody remember about split. In previous classes, we have discussed. So, using a single model, you can create dense retrieval, you can create, like, VM25 also, okay, and you can create, very similar to, light speed.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why that M3.
Krish NAik: everything that comes into… and it has multilingual support also. Okay, so as you can see, tense in this particular paper, so I'll be sharing the paper also in the chat, if you guys want to go through. Otherwise, directly, you can look into the implementations.
Krish NAik: So…
Krish NAik: The major character that comes, like, it is also used for retrieval, but there are multi-stage retrieval, using a single model. You do need to use different models.
Krish NAik: That's the core idea. Okay, so delve retrievals, parse retrieval, and multi-vector. Multi-vector retrieval, guys, can anybody tell me? Like, multi-vector retrieval, what is that?
Krish NAik: We guys have already discussed re-ranking.
Krish NAik: I think everybody remembers their two vectors goes into the cross inputting.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that we do refer as, multivectors, okay? And, that part…
Krish NAik: So, this is the core paper from where I got the idea. Let's a little bit discuss, and this is the actual repo, where you have the implementation. So, this particular library will be installing, and this is a very famous one. You can look into the number of stars in this project, 11.2K, used majorly for retrieval.
Krish NAik: Yes, multi-vector comes under hybrid approach only. Ariana?
Krish NAik: Okay, so the idea is enabling a single model we will try to perform. LLM will be separate, just like OpenAI, so that's why it's in the same notebook.
Krish NAik: Now, for the notebook, you have to, just, be sure that your Milverse container, because my integration that I have done, it is with the Milverse container. So just be sure your Milliverse service is working.
Krish NAik: In the previous week, we have already discussed, I've shared this script also with you, so directly, you can start. I think everybody remembers that Milverse part, okay? If it's new for you, quickly go to Millverse.
Krish NAik: installation docs, okay? So, I think from here you can actually get… So, in the last class, I've already discussed this part, how to set up this, so I'm not going to repeat myself. Okay, so please, just be sure the container is up.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine. Now, I think we can start with anti-gravity. All right.
Krish NAik: So, what are the, core objectives?
Krish NAik: Yep.
Krish NAik: So, right now, this is also another advanced retrieval. Okay, so the idea is to explore that multi-vector series through BGM3, very specifically released in 2024 by the Beijing team.
Krish NAik: And, totally open source, you can simply use it. So, 3 main things are there. The dense retrieval part, then you have your sparse retrieval, and finally you have your multivector. So, multi-vector, so generally the core, I can say, initialization comes from oldward, okay, which is another re-ranking implementation.
Krish NAik: So, this comes as a very expensive task, because I told you, like, re-ranking, I feel it's very, very expensive, because it always adds a bottleneck. So, every time using a re-ranker is not a solution, because the latency will be high for the final response that you will be getting.
Krish NAik: And, little bit, I have kept about the IBM research also. The core idea was to look into another research, which is based on,
Krish NAik: One is the, blended rack paper.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: The red paper, IBM.
Krish NAik: Definitely.
Krish NAik: This is another paper if you guys are interested in, okay, you can go through. This paper came in 2024. Okay, the core idea here is very, very similar, okay, but few things are different.
Krish NAik: And… and I feel that if you look into BM25, dense vector, sparse encoder, okay?
Krish NAik: All these things you guys have learned, so I'm telling you, actually, like, from where I take the implementations. Okay, so whenever I discuss something, behind that there will be some type of research.
Krish NAik: Always included. Now, the type of, I can say sparse and puder index that they have used, it's different. They have not used Splate, actually. Okay, and they have used ELACR. Now, ELACR comes from Elastic T. Okay, so this is another ELACR…
Krish NAik: elastic, so… Elasticsearch, ELACR.
Krish NAik: If you really go through this as a version V2, so right now, the upgraded version, so it is also used, so this is also a learnable one.
Krish NAik: So, I've not taught you about ELSER, but a simple implementation going forward, probably in some part that I'll be taking. So, this is another alternative of Split. So, simply, you can work with Split, because I feel the latest version of Split is really good, the V3 version.
Krish NAik: As compared to ELACR. But this is also used in production, both the themes.
Krish NAik: So, so, like, based on our previous discussion, this is the other paper. If you guys want, I will keep it in Notion, because again, for everyone, the entire paper discussion, I don't want to go through, but the poor things I'm talking about.
Krish NAik: And there is the other upgraded version of this particular paper, which came in the year 2025, last year. One is the MetaGen.
Krish NAik: Blended paper.
Krish NAik: I knew.
Krish NAik: Okay, so as you can see, this is 4th July. Now, I feel that this is very, very close to that, but few upgrades with respect to automatic metadata generation, that they have kept it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why this meta name comes. Just because of metadata.
Krish NAik: generation part that they have added. So, this particular implementation I'll be talking about, I feel this is much more recent, so probably now future classes. But in the last week, what I have discussed, so it's majorly based on blended rack from IPM. So you can actually look into that blended rack, and Metagen blended rack part I'll be discussing later, okay? So that's a little bit with respect to the research also, I'm telling you, so exactly from where I could
Krish NAik: Alright, now… Let's start, I think I can start with the notebook part.
Krish NAik: So, everybody just be sure that, in your system, the Melvas container is up.
Krish NAik: Hunt, let me see that everything is getting executed or not.
Krish NAik: I feel that, alright. The execution…
Krish NAik: worked for me fine. Okay, and you guys have already seen, so here I am doing the installation of flag embedding. Now, this is a new package, guys. Okay, without the flag embedding, I cannot use the functionalities of BJM3. Okay, so just be sure it is installed in your environment.
Krish NAik: Everybody please do that installation from the notebook, or directly from your terminal, whichever way you want to do it.
Krish NAik: Alright, everybody please do the installation, and then let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Just be sure that the libraries are getting imported successfully.
Krish NAik: Yes, Notion, I will add.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please have a check, and then let me know with a yes or not.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please do check that the import section is working. Only one person has told you it's done, because it's just a single package, the flag embedding, which comes from that one, okay? Please do the installation.
Krish NAik: Hmm…
Krish NAik: And, recently, anybody has checked, Gwen dropped a few new models.
Krish NAik: Anybody has done the testing on those models?
Krish NAik: the Quinn VL reed anchor from the Quinn family.
Krish NAik: really worked, good, I will say.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you want, you can do… these two models came around, the embedding model and the Rebanker. I tested the 2 billion one, it was working really good, and even the embedding, so you guys can also do your own test.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I felt just, like, these are good drops in the first initial week of January.
Krish NAik: Guys, I think everybody has done the installation, please let me know. Import works for everybody. Can we continue? Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Alright, everyone, fine. Let's proceed ahead.
Krish NAik: Alright, so if the import is working, the next thing is, the three models, the dense retrieval ones, sparse retrieval, all those definitions that I'll be doing in the next step.
Krish NAik: Now, let's load the dataset. So, as you can see, a sample dataset that I have kept with respect to the documents.
Krish NAik: This is similar, the core document that I have taken it, it's from that climate change document, which we have used it in the previous week, but for now, direct document definition.
Krish NAik: Alright, it will take some time. Okay, finally, the documents are loaded.
Krish NAik: Alright. Tarkith, please check Notion. Every time, don't ask for the Notion link, it's the same GitHub link.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, loading the BGM3 model, everybody please, download it, it will take some time, okay? So, even for me, I think it is already downloaded. In your case, it will take some time, so let's wait 1 minute. This is close to, 2GB.
Krish NAik: Yes, it will take some time, I know. That's why I will wait 1 minute.
Krish NAik: ASR models, Like, see, ASR model I'll be picking up in multimodal, division.
Krish NAik: When I'll be working with multimodal, right? In that project, you will be having everything, charts, images, and everything through that.
Krish NAik: Yes, it's more than 2GB.
Krish NAik: But, I know for everybody it will take time, so just let me know.
Krish NAik: And as you can see here, so I'm using half precision. I'm not using a full precision, because right now, even I'm on my CPU, I don't have a GPU, because the MPS which is available in my Mac, it's really not up to the map. So directly, I'm not using with…
Krish NAik: Floating point 32, rather than MP16, does the job in most of the cases.
Krish NAik: I think for everybody, the model is loaded, please let me know, I think I have waited enough for everyone.
Krish NAik: Rahul, please, check the docs. For the installation of Milverse, it's pretty much simple. I think Milverse, Milverse, okay. So, in the last class, I have already shared that route directly. Already, I, the script is there, if you look into the standalone. From there, you have to just write bash and start the container.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, comes generating all three embedding tags. Now, this is the core functionality, actually. Everybody just focus on this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, because directly, if you look into, the DJ M3
Krish NAik: can return all three types of data at once. This is the best thing. It means that you don't need separate implementations.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, as you can see, the return type, so model.encode, the model definition is the BGM3 data already, the initialization is done, and it's available in my local system. But you have to always remember the
Krish NAik: What is the dimension that comes? So here, for dense embeddings, the dimension is 1024.
Krish NAik: I am not using OpenAI embeddings, guys. Is this part clear?
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: just be clear, right now, only for the LLM part, I might use OpenA, but other than things with respect to embedding everything, that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, generally, like, with respect to these anchor, if you want to use it, this particular condition falls currently, which I have. You can actually change it to, true.
Krish NAik: Okay? So that particular option, so right here, generally, a lot of computation will come, because to, every token from every document, a unique vector will be created. Okay? So I don't want to do that high computation, in my system, because it gets a bit of laggy. But if you have IRAN, you can test it out.
Krish NAik: Now, by a single definition, if I, say, like, this is one of the best things, till now, there is not a single unified model. So that's why we say unified modeling.
Krish NAik: After BGM3, there are no such, I can say, other providers or anybody has done the research, where using a single model, you can actually do everything.
Krish NAik: Okay? But I feel that the support will be coming in future. Rather than using three separate models, why not focus on one model?
Krish NAik: VGM3 is an advanced embedding model. Don't think about advanced. It has the capability of performing a dense as well as a sparse as well as a re-ranker.
Krish NAik: Okay, so don't think about advanced embedding model.
Krish NAik: Because there are very few updates from the BEG community. Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Previously, we have done everything separately. That's the only thing.
Krish NAik: This time, everything can be done in one shot.
Krish NAik: just through a single call. That is the main difference.
Krish NAik: Okay? Amit, please check Notion, the GitHub link is exactly the same, just like last week.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, two things. So, one is the dense wig, okay, and one is the sparse wig. So, you can see here the return type of this. Through document embeddings, you can actually access this part.
Krish NAik: Now, let me execute this. This will take a little bit of time. Now, I'm just, sharing you now, this is the dimension, because I have 8 documents. For those 8 documents, 1024, which is a dense vector embedding which has been created. And, for our sparse vectors, like, it will be pretty much
Krish NAik: Okay, so in that particular case, I'm just showing you the top 10 terms. Now, you can simply add more print statements to debug exactly what is going on, okay?
Krish NAik: Well, like… Now, the poor part is done.
Krish NAik: Now, let me just connect to Melverse, because for VectorTV, I've used this one.
Krish NAik: Now, how many of you remember in the last class?
Krish NAik: that in whenever we are working with Milliverse, two things that comes. First of all, your collection schema, and the other one is your
Krish NAik: Field schema. First of all, you have to define your field schema. Once you have done the definition, then you can pass all those fields
Krish NAik: into your collection schema. Okay, just like last time, there is no change, guys, here. This part is exactly the same. So, what I have done, so there is just a check if the collection exists or not.
Krish NAik: If it is exist, then I will simply drop it. In your case, it won't be existing. Then I'm defining the fields, okay? Like, my primary key, the text, the dense vector, and the sparse vector.
Krish NAik: Okay, later on, you can add your multi-vector support also, through another feed.
Krish NAik: Then comes the schema definition, so here, feels that I have kept it, a simple schema. Now, this schema, I'll be passing it to my main collection.
Krish NAik: When I'll be creating it. A safer way to create. So, just like last time, last week I have discussed, it's the same thing.
Krish NAik: Alright, I feel that the collection got created, BGM3 Hybrid demo.
Krish NAik: Deepak is asking, the embeddings that are generated are present locally? Correct.
Krish NAik: deeper, it's available in your local machine only. Rishab is asking. Even through de-ranker and CoreGator, the latency of de-ranking will, still be there, yes, for sure.
Krish NAik: Ranking happens, okay, in the query phase, you have to understand, Vishop. So that's why the bottleneck will be there. You can't remove that bottleneck.
Krish NAik: Okay, and even I've kept it, somewhere, I think, within the comments, if you actually go through and mark down, I've kept it, like,
Krish NAik: somewhere around with respect to…
Krish NAik: Because the cons is slowest, because, really, like, this is one of the major cons with respect to read anchors, and Coher, everybody is using Coher, because it's a paid service, they have the
Krish NAik: highest quality of re-ranking, and even their re-ranker is very fast, as compared to all the open source re-ranker. I tested out the latest re-ranker from when, V3.ad got launched in January, okay, last week only. I was actually doing the testing, but I felt that somewhere, even this re-ranker that we have, this is also not very fast. The 80 billion is very, very slow.
Krish NAik: But this is also not very, very, I can say, fast.
Krish NAik: And actually, like, these re-rankers are for images also that you can process, not only for text. Okay, it has a real support, visual language understanding support, so really…
Krish NAik: Real models are actually slow as compared to text-based models.
Krish NAik: Alright, I think for everybody, this part, the creation is successful. If there is some problem with your Docker container, then probably this won't be getting executed, guys, okay? So please have a check on that particular set.
Krish NAik: Now, creating indexes. So, already the schema I have defined. Now, in the next step, we need to create the indexes. First of all, for my dense vector, so here, collection.createIntex. The collection is already initialized. In the next step, I'll be just creating that. And similarly, for sparse that I'm doing.
Krish NAik: For both of the indexes that I have created, the metric that I have used is IP, which is referred as inner product, or very close to cosine similarity.
Krish NAik: Alright, please have a check. I think for everybody, this should be created.
Krish NAik: Can you please, pardon about field schema and collection schema? So, whenever you are actually creating a collection, you need to decide what will be within that particular collection mode. So, we always, first of all, decide what are the different type of fields that we'll have, and then we try to create the collection.
Krish NAik: Alright, Moit, alright, already told. Saurabh, kindly share the links of the models you found good.
Krish NAik: Every week, new models come around, okay? So, just go to the homepage, like, always go to the homepage. This is the home page of Quinn, directly, sorry. Every organization has their homepage. In their homepage, you will always get the latest update.
Krish NAik: Well, now I think for everybody, is now the next step that
Krish NAik: collection with the index that is created. Now I'm ready to do the insert operation of my document.
Krish NAik: Now,
Krish NAik: As you can see here, so the next step is data insertion, or data upset operation that we'll be doing to our vector databases.
Krish NAik: So, right now… For my 8 unique documents, I have the primary keys.
Krish NAik: And then, all those documents have been uploaded to Milbus.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please have a check that, till this point, everything is working or not, because in the next step, I will start with the retrieval, because the data is available into vector databases, directly I can start.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Come down here.
Krish NAik: Multiple things that I've kept, dense only search, sparse-only search, okay, dense, sparse, hybrid, okay, and finally, cold butt re-ranking, that part also, I have kept it. And finally comes the full pipeline. So, step by step. So, first of all, for our dense search, okay, now this is the function which is responsible.
Krish NAik: So, search using only dense… so this is pure semantic search, the default retrieval technique.
Krish NAik: Okay, so there… here, it's nothing new.
Krish NAik: So, I have done the retrieval only for the Denver right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, now you have to remember, whenever you are performing, if you really look into this particular code syntax, so here, what I have done. The query that will be incoming
Krish NAik: First, I have to do the embedding for that, yes or no?
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Okay, and right now, I'm just doing a dense retrieval, so for others, I have actually turned false.
Krish NAik: Okay? So only the return type 10s that I'm worried about.
Krish NAik: Now, once I have the embedding, so I will be accessing it through the zeroth syntax, because I know in the zeroth index, the entire embedding will be available, and then directly, through collection.search, I can actually, apply a dense vector. So, like.
Krish NAik: I'm purely using pi milbers. Okay, so here I'm not using any lanchin or any other thing.
Krish NAik: Because I told you, every library has its own searching module. Even Viviate has it, Quadrant has it, so the syntax will be a little bit different. Okay, but here what I'm doing, collection.search.
Krish NAik: data that I am passing, based on which parameter, on top of which field you want to search, and finally, what is the metric through which? Like, inner product, which refers to the cosine similarity, number of probabilities, 10 that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Okay? Limit by default, it's the limit field, and the output field will be based on text.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just show you. So here, through a single for loop, I'm actually looking into this results parameter, as you can see.
Krish NAik: Okay, and let me access the score data we'll be getting.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the definition. I am not calling the function, I have just defined the function.
Krish NAik: So, the same query will be integrated, many other times, yes. Right now, Arun, I'm just showing you different retrievals through, file.
Krish NAik: Then in the next step, you have the sparse, or very similar implementation. Okay, now, this time, as lexical weights, so majorly, how many of you know the term lexical?
Krish NAik: In classical NLP, it has been used widely. For your sparse vectors, we call it lexical also. So sometimes, just remember, some people might not call it sparse vector, they might call it lexical vectors, so don't get confused.
Krish NAik: Okay, in interviews, sometimes they ask about that, so just be sure you are confident. At the end of the day, they are referring to sparse vector only.
Krish NAik: All right, now… I'm embedding the query, okay? Now, actually, this thing…
Krish NAik: This time, return dense false, and return sparse is equal to true. And the same thing that I have done.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, in the next step comes our search hybrid.
Krish NAik: Now, this time, both the things are returned true.
Krish NAik: Okay? Only for the multi-vector in Colbert that I have kept it for the re-ranker part.
Krish NAik: Okay, now I am query dense, and here, I'll be passing it. So, first of all, two definitions that I have done it. Okay, so I'm creating the search request.
Krish NAik: Because this time, I need to add them up, and then finally, so a simple CONCAT in simple terms. Two different search operations.
Krish NAik: So, the query tense list that I am passing.
Krish NAik: And finally, the sparse request. You can see two different type of requests that I have accessed. Now, these two requests, I need to pass it to the retriever in one shot. This is where RRF implementation, that will come into the picture.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, first of all, you need to define your search types, and then you need to pass it to your RRF ranker, as simple as that.
Krish NAik: Okay? Because at the end of the day, I think everybody remembers RRF, RSSF, in detail we have gone through in the last class. So, the same implementation that I have done, okay?
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: RSUSA, for that, you need to maintain your own file version system, okay? The one that you were asking. If you want to always keep a track of that, you have to understand.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, I think all my functions are done. Okay, and finally, coming to that cool part, the re-ranking part, because really, I don't need to save these vectors, so in this case, you will see that
Krish NAik: Very similar implementation, but for my dense, it is false, for my sparse, it is false. Okay, it means that the return type will only be based on my re-ranking, I can say.
Krish NAik: Only the return type of the re-anchor that I'm focused much more, based on the query.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, again, the model.encode. Okay, now can you see here, candidate text?
Krish NAik: Give?
Krish NAik: What do I refer to candidate text?
Krish NAik: What does Ready Ranking does, in simple terms?
Krish NAik: Candidate text is what? Can I say the output of a retriever? Simple retriever, yes or no. From there, you'll be getting the sequences, like chunk 1, chunk 2, chunk 3. So you actually need that particular information, so that refers here as candidate text.
Krish NAik: Alright, now from here, I'll be getting my encoded version, okay?
Krish NAik: And on top of that, once you have the document embeddings, finally, okay, from there, as you can see, document vector list, I'm just creating and I'm accessing that particular information by defining the array. Now, let's compute the score. Okay, so here's the re-ranking scores.
Krish NAik: That we will be combining. So here, as you can see, that, Maxim is there. So, the paper that I told you in BGM3, so very specifically, for similarity checking, they have used Maxim. Okay, so that's why this particular implementation of Maxim that I have done it. This is query to query. Okay, I will come to this particular part.
Krish NAik: When I'll be discussing about that, particular paper, so exactly what is cool, but.
Krish NAik: Because in high level, I told you, it's a re-ranker, but little bit, with respect to Colbert, there is a theory that is important, that I'll be discussing, so this part will be clear.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then finally, once you have that, you will be performing an arg sort operation. The idea is to look for the values with the highest index, so that's why arg with sort. And then finally, I will be keeping all my results inside this errand one. Okay? So, everything I have defined.
Krish NAik: Okay, guys, everything I have defined, now I will… I can run the full pipeline. Search full pipeline.
Krish NAik: Now, the query data will be incoming. Candidate limit, I've kept only 20 for now, you can increase this number.
Krish NAik: Final limit is equal to 3, it means that the final result from the re-ranker that I'll be getting as 3 only. Or you can increase this number to 5, 6, 10. Because I told you in the last class, whenever you are working with hybrid search, it's better to keep your top K value as much higher.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let me…
Krish NAik: Okay, so first of all, in this particular function, what are the things that we have? So, first of all, the candidates that will be arriving from the hybrid search.
Krish NAik: Okay, then accessing the candidates one by one, looking into the retrieved results, and finally here, I will be actually calling my Colbert re-ranking, so re-rank with
Krish NAik: Colbert, the function that I have defined above, that I am calling. And finally, I'll be looking into the result. Okay, so in one shot, everything. So all the functions I have defined above, now I'm just calling all those functions in one shot, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the function is ready. In the next step, directly, I'll be calling the search pipeline.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, this is a simple function through which I can actually access… now, this function will actually help me to display all the results in one shot, so this is just like a helper function to display things.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… let me just pass the query. I think I will be getting the response. Yes, I am getting the response. Everybody, please check whether you are getting the response. Amar Shaneva, sorry, if you don't mind, can you explain this notebook? Again, what to explain? Amar.
Krish NAik: If it's tough for you, you can ask me very specifically which part you didn't get it.
Krish NAik: Because here, the implementations are the same just like last week. Only the thing that I have changed, I'm not using any specific model for, like, doing a BM25 implementation. Using BGM3, I'm doing all the implementation. You want to look into step 6.
Krish NAik: Yes, in step 6, Exactly, so these are the retrievers that I have defined.
Krish NAik: This is your dens, then I've defined it for sparse, and then finally I've defined it for multivector.
Krish NAik: These are all the retriever definitions. I'm not using language directly, I'm using PyML bus.
Krish NAik: Okay? See, you have to understand the functionality. I cannot discuss every library, because the same functionality can be achieved by multiple libraries, so you have to always understand the concept.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you really go through all these concepts I have already discussed.
Krish NAik: Even custom implementations of RRF, RSF, these things I have already discussed, so I feel that you guys should be comfortable.
Krish NAik: The idea is not to take the same thing and just use it. The idea is to explore much more. If I change it to Viviate, or if I change it to quadrant, again, the syntax will change.
Krish NAik: The fundamental thing will never change. It means that there also, there will be sparse embedding, there also, there will be delts embedding, there also, there will be re-ranking-based embeddings, everything. The syntaxes might change.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let's focus on the final call, because I feel that
Krish NAik: the full search line is defined okay. I think for everybody, please do have a check with respect to the responses. Are you getting the responses? Because in one shot, I have done the definition, and I am actually, like, getting all the results.
Krish NAik: So, you can always have a check in the dense only if you look into the score. This is based on IP. Okay, IP refers to the inner product. The inner product value can be between 0 to infinity.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that is basically the limit that it goes around. So here, higher the value, the better the result. For tens only, we are getting 0.65, 0.600, 0.58,
Krish NAik: In sparse-only search, the results are, like, really low, I can say, because for sure, it won't have any semantic meaning. In hybrid, also, I can see that once I have done the inclusion of RRF, here also I don't feel the values are really good.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, this is the combination of dense parts with RF.
Krish NAik: Now, let me look into the result with respect to…
Krish NAik: These are index types E2317, so whenever you are defining, you have to define a field.
Krish NAik: inverse flat indexes. So generally, when you are saving it, it is in the format of IVF.
Krish NAik: In other vector databases, they don't very specifically mention that, but in Milverse, you have to do the definition.
Krish NAik: After getting the result, yes, you can do the evaluation with respect to RAGAS. Yes, ma'am, there is no restriction in that. Evaluation is totally separate. Like, on top of the results, you can apply RAGAS, Arise AI, PromptBench, any framework that you feel.
Krish NAik: But you need to actually access and look into the results. Now, finally, if you really look into
Krish NAik: Here, somehow, I feel the scores have increased, but really, the combination with hybrid and cold battery ranking that I feel.
Krish NAik: rank 1, rank 2. So, really, like, I feel that the, here, the main implementation, the hybrid is performing much better. In most of the rack systems, for sure, hybrid will perform better, as compared to your sparse encodings.
Krish NAik: Spars give you… you have to understand what is the mean use of spars, when you feel that your hybrid is not working.
Krish NAik: then only your sparse comes into the picture, okay? If you feel that your dense retrieval is really good.
Krish NAik: Really, like, sparse is just a fallback. If everything fails, then only look into sparse.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for sure, in our case, I can say the hybrid is working. And based on the results, if I really look into 0.6697, and here, if you looked into the results of the Dell search, I will say, yes, the…
Krish NAik: Here also, the result is 0.65. Now, this score, global warming, is primarily. Now, here, after applying re-ranking, the score has improved.
Krish NAik: So I can see that somehow.
Krish NAik: after applying on top of hybrid to cool but Sri Lanka, I'm getting better as well. So it's not necessary you combine everything.
Krish NAik: So, we can do all three embeddings using BGM3, am I right? Exactly correct, Mohint.
Krish NAik: for everything that we have done. Now, let's take a keyword query best. Okay, now, this is a very specific fossil fuel submission greenhouse gas that I've taken from one of the documents directly.
Krish NAik: Let's focus on that keyword part.
Krish NAik: Okay, and let's see the results.
Krish NAik: So, when you, look into, because simply I passed a… now you can see this is not very much clear also.
Krish NAik: When you look into the results with respect to dense search, okay, so here, fossil fuels, for sure, in this part.
Krish NAik: The results for fossil fuels, 0.68.
Krish NAik: Sparse-only search, at least 0.24 for the first one. You can see, if you have tried to compare it with your previous, sparse search, you will see that this result is at least better. Okay, so previously, how does global warming affect our planning?
Krish NAik: when I asked this one, so in this time, the sparse results were very, very low, if you really look into 0.13, 0.098, and 016. But this time, with respect to keywords, okay, I can say that, yes, the performance of the sparse vectors are better here.
Krish NAik: And even for the dense search also, it's getting better. Okay, and finally, if you try to do the combination of everything, dense path with RRR, finally, again, I can see. So, in this case, I can say that, really, that hybrid search requirement, because really the values are dropped.
Krish NAik: So, I'm just showing you examples. It's not necessary that every time you need your hybrid.
Krish NAik: Because most of the times, your dense will work, but what about when dense fails? Dense sparse comes into the picture?
Krish NAik: I hope you guys are getting it.
Krish NAik: It's not necessary. So, whenever you are taking the decision, how much weightage you will give, do use, dense or sparse, always give higher. That's why I tell at least use, like, 50% priority to dense, or use 60%. Give lesser priority to sparse.
Krish NAik: I've seen people using 70-30 ratio also, whenever you are applying that alpha value decision.
Krish NAik: That we have discussed.
Krish NAik: more than 90% of the times dense only works, okay? Sparse vectors is just…
Krish NAik: I can say, rarely, out of 1,000 times, probably 2 times that can sparse might help you.
Krish NAik: But it's a fallback strategy.
Krish NAik: Now, let's try to take a complex query. So, like, what are the feedback loops and cascading effects of climate changes on ecosystems? Like, really, this time, we have really kept things which is out of the context, a lot of things that are not in the documentary, okay?
Krish NAik: Now let's focus.
Krish NAik: On this one, okay. So here also, if I look into this complex one, so directly, if you look into the 10 search results.
Krish NAik: I can see that, yes, there is a drop, for sure. Previously, we were getting at least 0.66, 0.65, 0.69, but this time, yes, it has dropped.
Krish NAik: Then comes sparse-only search. So here you can see, really, this had dropped much lower as compared to our previous results.
Krish NAik: Finally, looking into…
Krish NAik: our hybrid result, 0.032, again, I will say the results of hybrid are not very good, because if you try to compare a building Arctic Eyes.
Krish NAik: melting RTIs. If you really look into the document, the document is very much same, but in the depth, now this document is actually different.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, with complex queries, generally you have to perform some type of query transformation. If certain keywords are not there, for sure, it will impact
Krish NAik: Your vector search.
Krish NAik: Okay, as well as, like, both the vector searches. It can be your dense, as well as it can be your sparse. So, most of the times, it's better to take an approach where you can perform some type of query transformations.
Krish NAik: Alright, now I'll be keeping it till this particular section, because there are some other added visualizations that I have kept. Really, if you want to explore that part, you can do it by using
Krish NAik: Alright, fine. So, this was one unified modeling. So, actually, the core concept that came last year, like, unified modeling, I will say majorly nobody is doing the research, only a few Chinese things that they are doing.
Krish NAik: And probably, I think, this year, they are planning to launch another unified model.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I feel that there's always… lesser your expenses, it can be run on a CPU, or you can host it somewhere for getting better performance.
Krish NAik: Alright, I think this notebook is done.
Krish NAik: Okay, and just be sure, that everything is done, just clean your vector TV, okay? Sometimes it might create, so I think this cleanup resources is there, everybody just delete whatever the thing, so the collection that you have created, it will be dropped.
Krish NAik: Because, again, if you try to rerun the notebook, and if you try to recreate the collection, you won't get an error, because in the code, I have already handled that part, dropped the collection. Otherwise, manually, also, you can delete it, because this is the place where I'm disconnecting with the vector databases.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just clean up. Cleanup is complete, alright.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so this is the first part, okay? So, this is much more with respect to research, but again, I feel that BGM3, as you can see, so this is…
Krish NAik: the paper from 2024. Okay, so it means that better models are out there in the market.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… probably some updates, you can directly… it's available in Olama, can you see? In Olama also, you can use it. So, I think everybody is using Olama in this class.
Krish NAik: So, through Olama, I'm using it through Hugging Face, but you can use it through Olama also.
Krish NAik: So, a very famous model. Actually, if you look into 3.1 million downloads, so from here, I feel that you will understand the meaning first.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: This part, we have gone through this one.
Krish NAik: Alright, take your 5 minutes, not an issue.
Krish NAik: I'm kidding.
Krish NAik: Everybody please go through the notebook, because this is the same thing, but the core implementation this time I have taken, it's through 5 milliliters, and as in the last class, even we have discussed 5mm, the same thing.
Krish NAik: Assignments, alright.
Krish NAik: No miss.
Krish NAik: Yeah, rather than assignment, because I'll be forming groups going forward, and I'll be giving you some tasks.
Krish NAik: Once this hybrid search and everything is done, then actually…
Krish NAik: Because now, little bit, with respect to that late interaction concept, we'll be talking about, theoretically, exactly what is happening.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please let me know, have you guys gone through the notebook?
Krish NAik: Go through that…
Krish NAik: Guys, let me know.
Krish NAik: You're ready
Krish NAik: how this is compared to GraphRag, and those are different things. There is nothing comparison that can be done with those.
Krish NAik: Graph right there, your vector database is only totally different, so you cannot do the comparison.
Krish NAik: In some cases, I can say GraphRag will perform better, but it's not necessary every time GraphRag will perform. In terms of outcomes, it depends upon the use case, really. There is not a single shot. This is better or this is better.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let's, little bit with respect to… Yes.
Krish NAik: This is Encoder-based network, that's why Bert is here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so whenever I write, word, always think from the encoder perspective only.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, as the name suggests, like, contextualize late interaction. Why that term comes as late interaction?
Krish NAik: Late interaction, guys, what do you… when that term comes late interaction. So you have to think from RAG perspective, why they use that term, late interaction?
Krish NAik: Because, if you remember in the re-ranker class, whenever I'm defining my re-ranker operation, You need the query.
Krish NAik: Without the query, you cannot perform a cross-enputing task.
Krish NAik: Okay? So that's why the late interaction, it means that
Krish NAik: After the retrieval, basically, the operation will come. Not after… it means that whenever you will be getting the query, it's not after retrieval, rather than you have to think. Without the query, there is nothing.
Krish NAik: We need the query.
Krish NAik: So, once you have the query, then only you can interact, okay? And the query comes into the late part only.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, generally, this is a neural retrieval technique.
Krish NAik: Very similar to DPR.
Krish NAik: Now, here also, you need two things.
Krish NAik: Okay? Because this late interaction, when you were defining in the architecture, its core purpose is document retrieval only. Now, the Colbert will encode both the things, your query as well as the document. That's why I've kept it RQOT. Okay, just like re-ranker definition.
Krish NAik: Now, multi-vector representation. Okay, so when I'm talking about here, multi-vector.
Krish NAik: Why I use the term multivector?
Krish NAik: I hope everybody understands, because we have two different vectors.
Krish NAik: your Q and D.
Krish NAik: Okay, that's why the name comes as multivector. Now, this multi-vector, directly you can do it with VGM3, or separately, you can use any relanchers from Kohar, Gwen, anything.
Krish NAik: But, always remember it's a good practice to keep from the same org. Okay, so it means that if you are using a Quen embedding model, try to use a Quen re-ranking model also.
Krish NAik: We have seen that the scores…
Krish NAik: are much better when you are actually sticking to the same organization. So, I feel that whenever you are actually using the embedding and the re-ranker, try to use it from the same family.
Krish NAik: LLM can be different.
Krish NAik: Okay, but at least that embedding, because the entire thing with respect to scoring and everything that happens, then it becomes from the same family. So I will say the representation is better, I feel. As compared, if you feel that you use OpenAI, therefore reliant, or you use Quinn, I feel that somehow the performance goes down.
Krish NAik: Fifth?
Krish NAik: Now, the first part… I'll be creating single vector per document. Okay, now here comes your maximum operation.
Krish NAik: Most of the times, how, you guys have, used cosine similarity. Very similar to that.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that we'll be computing the relevance.
Krish NAik: through the maximum similarity, so this maximum refers to as maximum similarity, guys, okay? So don't…
Krish NAik: Think about it as something different.
Krish NAik: It means that fundamentally, it uses cosine similarity.
Krish NAik: Now, what will happen? So, multiple vectors will be created, so you can use the term multiple contextualized vectors.
Krish NAik: Once the vectors are created with respect to your document and query, okay? And for query.
Krish NAik: It will be token level.
Krish NAik: If you remember, even in the anchor, it happened the same.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for every query in your query, if there are 10 different tokens, so…
Krish NAik: for 10 different, I can say, embeddings that will be created.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, late interaction, because the query and the document vectors
Krish NAik: after your initial search, then only your, cool battery will be activated. And what is the main purpose of the cool battery ranker? It will simply compute the relevance through your maximum similarity.
Krish NAik: This is the main stuff.
Krish NAik: That you have.
Krish NAik: Now, the question comes where you use a lot. Okay, so first of all, better semantic matching, it actually helps. It means that better semantic matching when I'm telling.
Krish NAik: So, this is a combination that I have showed you in the practical. Hybrid plus Colbert. There is no sparse. I feel that this particular combination is really good.
Krish NAik: Okay, let me just remove this hybrid, and I will keep it dense for now.
Krish NAik: you're dense, Plus… You're cool, but…
Krish NAik: So, whenever I say cool word, so in your mind, what should be the first thing?
Krish NAik: re-ranker. Nobody will say that we are doing re-ranking, but when you see Colbert, the main purpose is actually that we are doing a re-ranking operation.
Krish NAik: In the last week, can anybody tell me which rerun car model I have used in the notebook?
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: which re-ranking model I have used in the class.
Krish NAik: Everybody is wrong. Somebody is selling RRF, somebody is selling BM25, RRF, RS. The re-ranking model. How many of you? RRF and RSF, they are from hybrid search?
Krish NAik: I'm talking about re-ranking.
Krish NAik: Okay, now Ravi is telling, correct. I have used MS Marco Mini LM L6V2.
Krish NAik: I see. Don't get confused, okay? Whenever I see with respect to re-ranking, I'm not talking with respect to your R, R, F, and RSF, see. RSF…
Krish NAik: Okay, or RRF. They are part of hybrid search.
Krish NAik: If somebody asks you about hybrid search, then only you will say about this. If somebody asks you about read anchor, then totally the concept is different.
Krish NAik: In the last class, I have used MS Marco.
Krish NAik: Okay, that LMB2 version, that one.
Krish NAik: Don't get confused, keep your things. If somebody's talking with respect to RSF, simply it means hybrid search. That is the first step. Hybrid search means they are using dense with sparse.
Krish NAik: Both the things.
Krish NAik: Now, with respect to re-ranker, it is not necessary. R-ranking, you can apply on top of hybrid search, as well as directly on top of dense search result also, or only on top. So, re-ranking is totally a separate module. Don't get confused.
Krish NAik: Muthr, sir, but, we do re-ranking happens in hybrid search, right?
Krish NAik: We do re-ranking in hybrid search? No, we don't do.
Krish NAik: Hybrid search is totally different.
Krish NAik: Hybrid search, it's a simple, where you
Krish NAik: Do the retrieval by combining your densel sparse.
Krish NAik: From there, whatever the result that you'll be getting, on top of that, you apply re-ranking.
Krish NAik: Okay? Don't get confused on this one.
Krish NAik: Alright, so in the last week, I've used MS Marco LMV2, so that re-ranking model is available freely in Hugging Face, and that has been trained on the MS Marco dataset, so there is a dataset called MS Marco.
Krish NAik: So, that's why.
Krish NAik: That's why in the last class, always look into the code, at least go through, like, what is the re-ranking model? Okay, that way it will be done. Ranking is done after your retrieval, exactly correct. So that's why for re-ranking, we use the term late interaction.
Krish NAik: Okay, always remembered that. And very specifically, that's why I'm telling you with respect to cool birthday.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, most of the times, with respect to your BGM3, I can say, directly you can create it. I feel this is a much easier way, at any point of time, to do any type of definitions.
Krish NAik: Alright, now,
Krish NAik: In the last class, as we have discussed, re-ranker. Okay, now, Coolboard has multiple upgraded versions. Also, there's the Coolboard fee too. Okay, so you can test that out.
Krish NAik: Coldworth V2 version.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it's just, like, split, so every year, okay, around somewhere an upgraded version will come into the picture. And I feel that these upgrades are really good, but just remember, if you're actually changing the model, probably the improvement can be 2-3%. It's not like…
Krish NAik: 50% upgrade, okay, always remember, when every year, anything that comes up.
Krish NAik: Okay, now going forward, this will be your core pipeline, okay? So, it means that you have your tense vector, sparse vector, with multi-vector. Okay? So going forward, if I say these things to you, always remember, tense vector.
Krish NAik: Sparse vector, and multivector.
Krish NAik: So, what is the meaning of these three things, what I am doing?
Krish NAik: Quickly tell me, in chat, if I say that I am working with these 3 things, so exactly what do I mean?
Krish NAik: Quickly, tell me, guys, It means that… from here.
Krish NAik: both the results, I'll be getting my hybrid output.
Krish NAik: Once I have the output.
Krish NAik: on this output, I apply my multi-vector, okay? And finally, I get my re-ranked.
Krish NAik: Result, or re-ranked output here.
Krish NAik: So don't get confused RRF and RSF, okay? Those are from hybrid search. So, always remember, if directly these three things are written, it means that hybrid with re-ranking, as simple as that. Now, necessary, like, it is not, that every time.
Krish NAik: Sometimes we might define our spouse, but only it tells with
Krish NAik: Okay, so dense with re-ranking is also possible.
Krish NAik: People are using this approach also a lot.
Krish NAik: Okay, so dense plus re-ranker, but we never use sparse plus re-ranker. Just remember that. This, nobody uses. So, never…
Krish NAik: do this.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally, you apply a Colbert model or a re-ranking operation on top of hybrid search or dense search, it is much better. Don't apply it on top of your sparse one.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this was a poor, thing with respect to our
Krish NAik: Bgm3. Now, I can say that in 2024 this came, but I haven't seen any recent updates in 2025, okay?
Krish NAik: School board style.
Krish NAik: I will say that, yes, this works really good, because upgrades has been seen with respect to Colbert, like, 2020, 2022, multiple papers.
Krish NAik: Okay, and finally, so, put a cross mark, alright. Put a cross mark, alright, I will be putting it. Please use this combination, and never use this one.
Krish NAik: Hold on.
Krish NAik: Now, I will say that re-ranking is good, but again, it comes, because re-ranking is a post-retrieval. That's why in the last class I told you second stage retriever. Anybody remember those concepts?
Krish NAik: When I say second stage, Your retrievers.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, for example, just like your re-ranking in the last class, in your dense retrieval, you probably thought, let's find out the top K, and the top K value should be high.
Krish NAik: It's not like 3 or 4. At least keep 40, 50, 60, okay, sometimes people keep it 100. Okay, and then through Pulvert, or multi-vector re-rank, that we call it, from there, you can actually look into the top 10.
Krish NAik: Anything?
Krish NAik: Now, one important thing that I'm going to tell you, okay, because at the end of the day, you have to understand why VGM3 that I am suggesting.
Krish NAik: This part is interesting. Till now, in the last class, what I have told you, Generally, re-rankers are what?
Krish NAik: And what are embedding models? Quickly tell me this.
Krish NAik: In the last class, I told you.
Krish NAik: Generally, what type of… transformer architecture that re-rankers follows.
Krish NAik: Cross and quarters.
Krish NAik: Okay, and embedding follows. Which encoders?
Krish NAik: People are telling encoder only, embedding only. Nitish only told… see, guys, always remember, this is a bi-encoder.
Krish NAik: Probably in the next batch, I'll be keeping this concept, I feel.
Krish NAik: Alright, now… The thing that we have done, this with BGM3. Now, this is a unique case.
Krish NAik: Because here, actually, Our multi-vector that is getting, it is based on
Krish NAik: By encoding.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Bioencoders are much faster as compared to your cross-encoders.
Krish NAik: Always remember that, okay? Buy encoders, Always faster.
Krish NAik: Then… cross encoders.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, in this case, actually, it's not a cross encoder. That's why I feel that this was one of the most unique ones.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, every re-ranking model that's based on cross-encoders only.
Krish NAik: Okay, always remember, buy-in quotas are very, very fast, as compared to cross-end quotas.
Krish NAik: actually query and context, separately, which means it will grow syllabens. So, if you try to, compare
Krish NAik: The accuracy, really, cross-encoders will perform better, I feel, always.
Krish NAik: But if you're using the complete BGM3, like, BGM3 pipeline, where it dense and everything, if you use it in one shot, then actually some…
Krish NAik: cases, I can say it performs better.
Krish NAik: It's not every time your BGM3 approach will work. I feel that most of the times, other cross-encoder re-ranker models, they perform much better. Okay, but this is a unique case where you actually use a bi-encoder to do re-ranking.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, there are no such cases. Every case, there is a cross input.
Krish NAik: Always remember to.
Krish NAik: So that's why I thought about… let's discuss a little bit about BGM3.
Krish NAik: And, generally, I've seen people using BGM3, and they do, like, fine-tuning, actually, okay, on top of custom data set. But again, that's a separate thing.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, so…
Krish NAik: Always remember, this is a very unique case for BGM3, where you use a… in interviews, sometimes, if somebody asks you, always remember that. Majorly, all of your anchors are based on cross-encoders, but this is the only case where you actually use that.
Krish NAik: Yeah, your embedding model is actually based on it, by encoding thing.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think this is a, core part, okay, and now I will jump into something else.
Krish NAik: Encoding parts, probably, I will write with respect to break.
Krish NAik: I don't feel afraid of…
Krish NAik: Alright, let's take a break of 10 minutes on that. Deepak, alright, I won't be explaining, these are the fundamentals that come from transformers.
Krish NAik: Deepug.
Krish NAik: Melind is asking, why re-ranking need encoders? Otherwise, how you will encode your incoming query or the context of the chunk? There has to be some type of encoding mechanism, Melind. Otherwise, it won't work.
Krish NAik: That's why it is faster than quantitates every one, because by encoding models will be for sure faster as compared to cross-encoding models.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, yesterday, after this, we'll be starting Text2SQL.
Krish NAik: Thanks for the introduction, why it's important. Why it's important? Because that unified modeling concept is only there in BGN. There are no other concepts.
Krish NAik: With respect to unified model, we tell now.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let me start the timer, and then I think we can… Where is the block?
Krish NAik: Digital.
Krish NAik: I think this is not quite necessarily the issue.
Krish NAik: Oh, one of them.
Krish NAik: All right, Soham, I think… okay. In the mail, only directly when you are there, because today, again, at night, 8 to… so, before 8, if it is possible, you can let me know.
Krish NAik: Kohlbert is a real anchor.
Krish NAik: Moidwitharia.
Krish NAik: Who, what is a re-ranker?
Krish NAik: I think biology, in your PDF, you will be having that, PDF of climate change. Please check, I think the folder is their new data docs.
Krish NAik: Yes, I think 4 to 5, 5.30 is, that is fine.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me start the timer, okay? Then we'll be back, and then we will start Text2SQL.
Krish NAik: SK is asking for RAG query resource perspective, which one is better, VGM recombining in one combined query, or separate as in earlier?
Krish NAik: I prefer, like, BGM3 with hybrid, plus
Krish NAik: your re-ranking. Generally, including sparse is not my priority aspect.
Krish NAik: Alright, in the chat…
Krish NAik: A few things with respect to the spectrum of buy encoding cross. Okay, few questions are coming with respect to buy encoders, cross encoders…
Krish NAik: Okay, and Colbert. Okay, alright. Let me clarify, then I will take just 5 minutes.
Krish NAik: explaining this, okay? So…
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, fine. Let me just take a simple example with respect to calculations, exactly how it is different.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: Okay, so a little bit, because it looks like, understanding the spectrum is also important, so that part.
Krish NAik: So, as I told, Colbert, okay, so you have to remember, Colbert, Isa?
Krish NAik: by importer architecture.
Krish NAik: Okay, don't think your Colbert is a cross-encoder. Colbert is not a cross-encoder, it's a bi-encoder architecture. Okay, but the twist here is, simply.
Krish NAik: Okay, a small twist is there.
Krish NAik: Through late interaction.
Krish NAik: It acts as a… Cross and quota.
Krish NAik: Okay? Like…
Krish NAik: The final, I can say, the output, it will be, like, cross-encoder quality, but the quality will be low.
Krish NAik: Okay? Always remember that. So, in simple terms, if I put here, so I will say, buy encoder.
Krish NAik: Okay? And then in between, I will put Colbert.
Krish NAik: Okay, and finally comes your cross encoder.
Krish NAik: So, your biencoder, this will be fast.
Krish NAik: But less accuracy, always remember.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this will be slow.
Krish NAik: But with high accuracy.
Krish NAik: Okay? I think for everybody, bi-encoder, colibert, and cross-encoder is clear in your mind?
Krish NAik: Okay? As the terms say, by encoder, it means that the encoding will be separate for your query and doc.
Krish NAik: Okay? Here, it will be joined.
Krish NAik: Is this part clear? Join encoding.
Krish NAik: The same thing happens. As I have told, culvert is a biencoder, so in culvert also, separately, encoding happens.
Krish NAik: Okay, and one important thing.
Krish NAik: With respect to attention, because we always speak with respect to self-attention, very specifically.
Krish NAik: So, most of the times, in buying quarters, you don't have a query doc attendancy.
Krish NAik: There's a concept of query-to-doc attention.
Krish NAik: This is not available in bi-encoders.
Krish NAik: Okay. Amen?
Krish NAik: in by encoders.
Krish NAik: But, in Colbert, it is available, okay? In Colbert.
Krish NAik: So, because, whenever you are doing a re-racking operation, you need this query doc attention functionality. Other than that, the result won't be very good. Okay, so in Colbert, you have this particular functionality, but most YAM coders don't have this one.
Krish NAik: And simple terms with respect to the computing part, I will just say, okay, with respect to vector computing.
Krish NAik: So, exactly how it will look like.
Krish NAik: In your buy encoders, how it will happen, guys? In your buy encoder, if I say…
Krish NAik: you have, two things. So, let's take our query, okay, for your query that you will have, and you will talk.
Krish NAik: as… Separately inputting will happen.
Krish NAik: Okay, I can say here, EE stands for encode right now. So, most of the times, a CLS token that will come into the picture, and then probably your vector will be here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so whichever vector are basically numbers that will come into the picture. And similarly for your dog, again, another embedding technique with CLS, and then finally this vector.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, these two vectors, you need to combine, because you need to actually get the final scores.
Krish NAik: So here, the scoring mechanism will be based on, if I take query, like, Q for now, okay, E, Q,
Krish NAik: a dot product with ED.
Krish NAik: So this is how bi-encoders will compute the score. Okay, so this is how your actual vector encoding will look like.
Krish NAik: Similarly, if I say with respect to Colbert, in Colbert, what is the main difference? I told you about Mattson.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that maximum will come.
Krish NAik: In Colbert.
Krish NAik: This is the only difference with respect to score computation, because here, maximum will come into the picture.
Krish NAik: Okay? Maxim on top of what? Your EQ?
Krish NAik: comma ET. So this is where the only thing changed that happens. In cross-encoder, it's totally different.
Krish NAik: Cross encoders, both, the encodings are done together. Okay, a joint encoding operation that happens.
Krish NAik: in cross-empurpose.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, joint embedding. No separate embedding happens, so that's why, in a single one only, that's why I'd say Q Comedy.
Krish NAik: Through this.
Krish NAik: That's the only difference. In cold water, that maximum similarity. Otherwise, in biencoders, they don't use it, so directly, pretty much a dot encoder.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think everybody got the clarity. I don't think there should be any other confu- confusion. I have told you with respect to that particular approach also.
Krish NAik: So, Hari is telling, they compress an entire document into a single vector, and making them the fastest for such correct. Hari, covert late interaction, word-to-word, yes. So, token-level interaction that happens, that's why word-to-word, hurry correct.
Krish NAik: Cross-encoders together finally re-ranking through this bar are too slow for searching large databases, exactly correct.
Krish NAik: CLS, no, that is a token, a classification token, it refers to as.
Krish NAik: the maximum similarity gets calculated through your cosine similarity, JB.
Krish NAik: In terms of cost, cross-encoders will be, less expensive. No, it won't be less. That is the highest level of computation, cross-encoders.
Krish NAik: The computational will be high, expensive, JV there. For buy encoders, it's towards the lower cent.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright. Works as a read anchor, yes, it works as a read anchor, but majorly all re-ranking models are based on cross-encoding. Only Colbert is a difference, Mohit Besari. That is a unique exception, always keep it in your mind.
Krish NAik: That's why I told you with respect to your vector computation also exactly how it happens. All right, now I think, we are good to go ahead with the next part.
Krish NAik: So, let me start sharing my screen. I think I need to get to the GitHub report.
Krish NAik: So, I think for my GitHub… Hmm… slash advanced tutorials, identifying…
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think it texts to SQL, everybody?
Krish NAik: I'm sharing, please take a clone of this report.
Krish NAik: Alright, this deployment is actually very high.
Krish NAik: the next deployment that we have in the next project, okay, which will take a lot of time, close to 25 minutes, a lot of EU bids are there.
Krish NAik: Just because of one package, Tesseract.
Krish NAik: It really takes a lot of time.
Krish NAik: Everybody please take a clone of Text2SQL.
Krish NAik: And then let me know in the chat, once you have done, okay, I think the requirement.txt is also there. Please try to install everything in your system.
Krish NAik: Okay, so take a clone… And please…
Krish NAik: I think I can close this vector… table.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine, just be sure you have that .env file. Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think at least pass your OpenAI API key, I think that is the main one.
Krish NAik: For your fourth notebook, sample connection with respect to Postgres that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: and rest of the cases, it's SQLite, only I have taken for now. Okay, just pass your OpenAI API key.
Krish NAik: And just be sure the first part is working okay. Just check with respect to the…
Krish NAik: Import required, like, the stack part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please let me know in the chat whether the setup is done.
Krish NAik: Okay, and please check that the first cell is working fine.
Krish NAik: The required ones.
Krish NAik: Narula, Neeraj, Narula is saying, so there is no need to add a re-ranker if we are using pool, but yes.
Krish NAik: Correct.
Krish NAik: Done, guys, everybody?
Krish NAik: Alright, now,
Krish NAik: If the first cell is working fine, so majorly, I know that the Llama Index part, everything is configured in your case, and right now I'm working with OpenAI.
Krish NAik: So, the next step is basically to check that everything is up or not, okay? So, opening API key found, alright.
Krish NAik: Now, defining my, global settings. Okay, so this is my OpenAI and GPT-4 Room Mini, the OpenAI key that I have passed.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, to do any type of SQL task, first, I need some type of sample operation. Okay, a sample data. So, for that, I am just using SQLite for now. Okay, to create a database.
Krish NAik: So here I've defined the schema. Okay, the employees table and the department table. Now I'll be creating all the objects.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think somewhere here.
Krish NAik: That a basiccompany.db file will be created.
Krish NAik: I think this particular format, everybody is comfortable with. This is completely SQL. Very, very simple. I have used only SQLite. Later on in the project, I have used Superbase, Postgres proper, but for our initial learning, I've just kept it simple.
Krish NAik: Please have a check if there is some issue with respect to your, SQL alchemy, okay, because sometimes this package creates an issue, this pie…
Krish NAik: this, driver, but I think there won't be any problem with respect to your SQL alchemy. If you are getting any problem, please have a check on top of the version.
Krish NAik: Alright, I think for everybody, the tables are getting created. Please let me know.
Krish NAik: In the chat, please let me know, guys, with a yes or no.
Krish NAik: Yes? Alright, fine. Then I'll be inserting some sample data.
Krish NAik: Because SQL alchemy, in… when we teach Python, we teach SQL Alchemy to students, so, pretty much.
Krish NAik: fundamental things. Alright, inserted 4 documents and 10 employees, alright, fine. With respect to the department's done, with respect to the employer's done, okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let me just do a verification of the data. Alright, so this is finally… So, here I'm using pd.readSQL, because directly I can pass it, and I can fire some queries, so select star from document, select star from employees, limit to 5,
Krish NAik: This is a simple, like, head-like operation, although that you can perform directly on EPF steel.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here I have done the verification, so I think for you also it will work.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, Llama Index has this NL SQL table query chain.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a direct query engine which is available. I feel that for text-to-SQL type of tasks, it's always better to go ahead with Lama Index as compared to Langchen. The LangChan approach is pretty much tool-based approach, okay, which I'm not really fan of. Okay, so if you guys decide to explore Langchen part.
Krish NAik: The same thing you can, but I feel that Llama Index is much powerful. So, for this particular task, I have picked up Llama.
Krish NAik: Okay, but the same thing can be done in Lanching. The functionalities are equally available.
Krish NAik: No,
Krish NAik: Using this, there are multiple query engines, as you know, in Llama Index, the query engines are actually more than helpful and powerful as compared to line-chain, retrieval engines.
Krish NAik: So, here, first of all, SQL database, and here I'm including what are the tables that needs to be needed, okay? So, this is where your actual SQL ultimate driver that I am using it.
Krish NAik: So, here's simple things, sequel.getUsable table names, single table info, on top of employees and departments.
Krish NAik: checking with respect to our SQL database object, and everything looks fine to me.
Krish NAik: Now, let's try to initialize our Llama Index query engine. In the query engine, directly, you can see the SQL database I have passed. In that SQL database works as the tables that you need. So, probably, if you have 10 tables, 20 tables, 100 tables, all these things, you can keep it.
Krish NAik: And this one, so… I have passed it now.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is where I have fired some custom queries, as you can see. So, these are simple SQL queries. Now, the idea is to generate the SQL using an LNF.
Krish NAik: So, this NL SQL table query engine will actually help me to generate the SQL that I'll be executed.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think the initialization of our query engine through Llama Index is done. We are ready to process, okay? Now, let's take, like, how many employees are there in total? Okay, now let's fire the query. So, query is defined, query.engine.query, I'm passing the query, let's look into the response.
Krish NAik: Okay, so how the response looks like.
Krish NAik: Alright, it is first of all getting both the table info, table, department, okay? And now, predicted SQL query.
Krish NAik: Okay, because finally the answer that you were getting, there are a total 10 employees.
Krish NAik: Please have a check, and then let me know
Krish NAik: Are we getting the correct result?
Krish NAik: Everybody, please check it.
Krish NAik: Please check it, guys. Because, see, there are multiple queries. How many employees are in each department?
Krish NAik: Table schema,
Krish NAik: Why it is not taking the table? Actually, you are directly passing both the tables, San Kumar. When you have actually created the query engine here, you have passed both the tables through that, it access
Krish NAik: So, in vana.ai, you have the capability of passing the entire schema as a context.
Krish NAik: That is, powerful, that's why I kept it in your project. But here, I feel that, very specifically for text-to-SQL type of tasks, neither Langchen, neither is good. Generally, everybody creates a hybrid approach, few things from Langchen and few things from Lama Index.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Moit, so how, we could not get it is converted from text to SQL. Actually, you pass the information.
Krish NAik: the table-related information, that particular context get into the, LLM. Through that, it actually tries to generate that.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, if you want to explore this particular engine, okay, so you can explore this engine also. So, this is the core engine that happens, so simply LAMA index.
Krish NAik: This is the main query engine.
Krish NAik: That you have, so I think I can increase it.
Krish NAik: As you can see, there are multiple retrievers. Right now, I'm using this one, the major one, the NLSQL retriever. Similarly, you have a PGVectorSQL. Now, when you're directly working with Postgres, then you can use it.
Krish NAik: Did we put to the LLM in settings for 10 years? We have passed the LLM. Without the LLM, how we can generate?
Krish NAik: the actual… the SQL query which is getting generated, it is from the LLM. Without the LLM, we cannot do it.
Krish NAik: If you… if your database is bigger, this actually takes a lot of time. It's not super fast. In that case, you can actually, pass the, context schema. Now, that particular functionality is actually available in Vanan, okay? Here, you have to understand
Krish NAik: These libraries are not only built to perform text-to-SQL tag. Llama, Windows, and Lansion, they have other multiple functionalities.
Krish NAik: But Vana.ai is highly specialized to do this task only. Okay, so that's why there you will have much more functionalities as compared. But this is the main one you can look into.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let's get back here. Similarly, you can fire up the other queries also, I think, based on that, you'll be getting the response.
Krish NAik: model you can pick up. GPT-4, I feel that it works good, but again, that is towards the higher side.
Krish NAik: Engineering, 4 employees, sales, 3 employees, marketing, 2 employees, so you will see that, yes, you will be getting good results.
Krish NAik: Now calculating the salary…
Krish NAik: Okay, so the average salary, all those calculations, that is directly taken care of.
Krish NAik: To frame the query, it needs a table right here. Without the tables, it cannot actually frame the query monogram. So you have to always pass the table. The idea is that once you pass the table, from there, it actually tries to get the context of… or basically the schema as a context from each table.
Krish NAik: Okay, what are the topmost, again.
Krish NAik: highest one, which department has the highest budget, all under 6 queries, I have kept it, so you can actually do the testing and then let me know that whether it's throwing the right result or not. If you are not sure about, you have the SQL query also, okay? And right now, you are not getting an explanation.
Krish NAik: So, really what is happening, it's actually showing you the query, but later on, I'll be showing you in Vana.ai, you can actually get the explanation also, so that everything, how it is working step by step.
Krish NAik: An explainer agent is there, but here in Langchain and Llama Index, that particular feature is totally missing.
Krish NAik: Yes, it can work with DynamoDB tables, correct. It can work.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this is a complex query, okay, with a joint operation, show me the employees in the engineering department with their salaries. Again, if I try to fire this up, this will also work.
Krish NAik: Along with their salad, it's fine.
Krish NAik: Now, if you want to directly fire up, so inspect the generated SQL. Now, this I have already shown you, okay, but if you want to actually access the metadata, if you feel that if it is helpful to you, okay, now, this is the actual metadata that gets generated.
Krish NAik: Like, what are the main keys, the SQL query that has been generated, okay?
Krish NAik: So, this is a high-level breakdown.
Krish NAik: If you really look into the metadata.
Krish NAik: But really, I feel that that's metadata, step by step, first of all, let's look into the department, then look into the salary, then look into that engineering part.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, step by step, I feel that, okay, now this is how it's thinking strategy.
Krish NAik: But I feel the explanation is not really up to that particular mark.
Krish NAik: locate it.
Krish NAik: Oh, great.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the most simplest way, so you can actually test it out. Now, see, now, the idea is that you might have some type of ambiguous query, okay? Now, here I have not created any specific, set of keywords that how to do the classification.
Krish NAik: actually when you will be doing the integration with any RAG-based system. So, first of all, you have to analyze that whether it's a SQL query or not.
Krish NAik: If it is SQL query, then only this retriever engine will be invoked.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, your normal text-based approach, your hybrid search, it means that you need to define some type of logic-based system based on some keywords.
Krish NAik: And a LLM can generate wrong query.
Krish NAik: Generally, in the case of Langchain and Llama Index, it can be.
Krish NAik: biopsy. Now, when… see, this is an ambiguous query, show me every one. Now, every one means…
Krish NAik: At the end of the day, we are talking about some users also. So, show me everyone, everyone related to employees.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here… here is the list of all employees along with their positions. That has been written, and I feel that at least
Krish NAik: Though I passed a pretty much ambiguous query, the query engine returned me pretty much right reserves.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: No.
Krish NAik: Let's take a non-existent column example also. So, what is the age of each employee?
Krish NAik: Okay, in this case, what will happen?
Krish NAik: Yes, if the information is not available, what will happen, guys?
Krish NAik: Okay, now it's telling you one approach, okay? Answer to determine the age of the employer, we can calculate the difference between the current date and their higher date.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, do you think that in this way you can get the age of each employee?
Krish NAik: Okay, now this age is coming, you can think about the working age. Okay, or probably, like, for how much time that guy has been working in that particular organization. So here, simply, this is an error.
Krish NAik: So that's why I'm telling, it means that if there is no information only, okay, at any point of time, you will get an error. These type of things, always, LLM will make a mistake.
Krish NAik: Alright, now coming to some type of query refinement, because this is that you have to do from your site, or a very specific
Krish NAik: A query transformation task that you have to keep if the queries are ambiguous.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally, you can pick up only 3 words, 4 words, 5 words, try to analyze the context, and if you're not really getting
Krish NAik: Okay, what is the distinct operation that needs to be applied? In that case, it's better to make your query much more specific.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, show me some employees. Okay, so some employees, really, we don't know what is.
Krish NAik: And list all employers had after. Okay, now, this is a better one, at least, I can say, than both the cases, the results that you can look into.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, limit 5, so that sum is coming, and more specific query, so this is better. So, the idea is whenever you are working with text-to-SQL, you need to perform some type of query transformation.
Krish NAik: It means that the user might not pass the correct keywords, but you need to reframe that, at least in your inner working, that, okay, now this is actually the requirement in that way.
Krish NAik: You can create a logic. It means that if you feel that some information is asked, which is not available totally in the table, then you can return that, yes, this particular information is not available, so this query cannot be processed. In that way, also, you can perform.
Krish NAik: Arun is asking, what is the best strategy for it, Mithesh, regarding which one you want to know the best strategy? Here, multiple logics will come, which I've kept it in the project, but for now, initial level, because there I'm not working with Llama.
Krish NAik: Arun is asking, works by using a large language model to translate the natural language into executable queries. Does the LLM have the knowledge of the database? Yes.
Krish NAik: During your retrieval part, you pass that to the query engineer, the table. If you don't pass the table information, how it will understand?
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: How to guard against errors? So, actually, you can pass the table schema as context. Okay, through that, you can actually keep a track that these are the columns. If something comes out of the system, then you can simply say that this, the SQL query cannot be generated in that case.
Krish NAik: Alright, some best practices again, so it's… the idea is always to include the tables without
Krish NAik: Now, see, at any point of time, this get usability table info. That's why I'm showing you this particular operation. So just be sure on whichever table you want to do the operation, it is available and accessible.
Krish NAik: Alright, then comes, based on…
Krish NAik: And these type of keywords, you can actually do an operation and you can keep it. Okay, now, these operations, I have kept it in your project.
Krish NAik: Okay? Like, you can actually select, like, drop, delete, update, insert, truncate, exact, execute. Okay, is the query safe or not? So, based on that, you can actually take an action.
Krish NAik: Then comes, context management. Okay, so…
Krish NAik: The idea is to provide much more information. Okay, so here, with respect to our query, you can see a much… a bigger query that we have processed. So from here, you can perform a strip.
Krish NAik: So, two level of queries.
Krish NAik: Based on, show me all the ICs with the salads, so individual contributor.
Krish NAik: Based on that, I've generated a context on top of that I'm performing. So, there are multiple ways, I'm just showing you a few examples right now.
Krish NAik: Here we pass the schema, but still got the error. Here we pass the schema, but, still got the error. Error with respect to what MS, you can let me know.
Krish NAik: Yes, it is dynamic. The table schema, it will be dynamically understood. It means that information will be passed to that particular LLM.
Krish NAik: Okay, the H column in it, yes.
Krish NAik: And now, one thing, if you change the LLM, the responses can be different. You can test it out, that one also. Because if I change the LLM, I have seen that, yes, it failed.
Krish NAik: Okay, it doesn't fail. The generation, the quality of generation, generally, I feel that always you should go with higher model.
Krish NAik: Low models are not really good, okay? Like, any model less than 2 billion parameter, never use it for text-to-SQL type of task.
Krish NAik: It's better always try to stick to higher parameter models, at least 70 billion parameters. They are much better.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, there are some exercises that you can try it out.
Krish NAik: Okay, with respect to other operations that we have.
Krish NAik: Coding model… coding models are totally separate things.
Krish NAik: OT news models are totally separate. In those cases,
Krish NAik: For, coding models, I prefer, like, 23, Coder, those type of models I'll be picked up. Then you have Code Strawl.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Nobodesh Sharma, for your effort.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this part with respect to the basics that we have gone through.
Krish NAik: Now, a little bit, let's take it to the next level.
Krish NAik: Now I'll be talking about the next. Is ChatGPT, based on questions, how it changes the model to answer?
Krish NAik: Use these cases to develop from text-to-visual summary deriving insights to use Gemini models to generate queries. Yes, you can use Gemini modules, but don't use flash. I feel that somewhere. The new flash is good, 3.1, but 2.5 flash, not really up to the market.
Krish NAik: Alright, now dynamic table retrieval, okay? Now, this is…
Krish NAik: The next one, the SQL table retrieval engine, this time, I have changed. So, for your basic type of task, NL query engine status file, but this time, I have changed the SQL table, so the next engine that you have here.
Krish NAik: Okay, the SQL table retriever. So, this one I'm using. And if you really look into the property, the SQL retriever is actually based on NL SQL.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: But the base class is the base SQL retrievers. You have to understand the core, application or the fundamental objective. It can be achieved through anal SQL as the high-level one.
Krish NAik: So, let's set up the configuration this time.
Krish NAik: How to guard it? Simply say, you have to keep it as a prompt MS. If something is not available, simply say that it is not available.
Krish NAik: You can write your custom logic, and you can always do the manipulation.
Krish NAik: Alright, so now, moving to the next one. So here, the query engine I have changed from NL SQL to SQL table retriever Query Engine.
Krish NAik: Now, I think all my library inputs are working fine. Let me define my LLM.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this time, let's first of all, perform a test connection that everything is working fine, database, all right.
Krish NAik: So here, also, SQLite, mutually. Let me pass…
Krish NAik: I need to generate some sample data.
Krish NAik: Okay, so first of all, this is with respect to the customers table that I am creating, so you can actually look into the customer's DF, exactly what it looks like. Then you have a products table, okay, and then, finally, product reviews.
Krish NAik: Okay, so 3 tables that I have taken. One is your…
Krish NAik: The customer, product, and the reviews.
Krish NAik: Now, let's take directly, because these are based on data frame, so a 2SV operation that I'm doing.
Krish NAik: Okay, orders… it's not defined, it's still in something, have I missed it? Okay, let me just check.
Krish NAik: Alright, now it is executed. So, customers, product, orders, and reviews. Okay, so these are the main tables that I have taken.
Krish NAik: Now, in the next step, you can see my SQL database.
Krish NAik: Here, the core engine that I'll be passing.
Krish NAik: Okay, my main engine, and right now here, very specifically, I'm telling, again, include tables.
Krish NAik: I bet so… First of all, again, what I have not defined here.
Krish NAik: Sql database engine, this part, value error, not found in the databases.
Krish NAik: Okay, this, I think I have not connected because of that, yes.
Krish NAik: Now, it's done.
Krish NAik: Now, what is this operation?
Krish NAik: This is simple pandas operation, pandas to SQL that I have done.
Krish NAik: I have loaded the CSV files in the database. I think everybody is familiar with this. This is a pure pandas, or a polar operation. In Polars, also, you do the same way. Or in pandas, or in FireDucks, anywhere.
Krish NAik: Raj, please let me know.
Krish NAik: First of all, I have generated sample data for the four CSVs. That's why I created the CSVs. You can actually look into here, your CSV files will be there. You can directly look into all these CSV files, so exactly what is the data that got generated.
Krish NAik: please do have a check on the CSV files. This is a custom data that I created. Simply random.
Krish NAik: Right now, for this fake data, I have not used any library. Otherwise, you can use Faker. Okay, using Faker, you can actually generate. In the main project, I'll be using Faker.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, loading the data frames into SQLite, alright. Let me perform this insect schema, okay?
Krish NAik: Alright, I can see the tables are accessible.
Krish NAik: For our databases.
Krish NAik: Now, let's put some tables
Krish NAik: schema context. Okay, now this one, I feel it's much powerful, because here you can pass your context string.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, most of the times, if you have 1,000 tables, do you think that you will write manually? You will use an LLM to generate this particular feed?
Krish NAik: If you have a million tables, okay, for sure you cannot write, but this is very, very… this is actual context information, so within this table, exactly what are the things that you have.
Krish NAik: That's why, first, I started with something basic. Now, let's add that thing manually.
Krish NAik: That's why I've taken the example.
Krish NAik: Let me know, guys, is this part clear?
Krish NAik: or not.
Krish NAik: Here, I have taken simple schemas, and here I am defining what is the context among each table.
Krish NAik: This is pure context.
Krish NAik: because when you have more tables, the other NL query engine, really, like.
Krish NAik: The main con that I feel that here, in this one, when you are actually defining, okay, here I have taken simple 3 tables or 4 tables, it becomes much easier to define it in one shot.
Krish NAik: Where is that one?
Krish NAik: my query engine just a bit. I think later on it will come. Okay. Because this particular schema context, even VANA.ai, if I show you with respect to VANA, there also… you will be passing the entire schema context, rather than keeping it in this one.
Krish NAik: For every table, there, you define that, but a very similar approach.
Krish NAik: In LandChain, passing the context schema, that particular feature is not there. Okay, so… but in Lama Index, this feature is there. I feel that this is a much powerful feature.
Krish NAik: Okay, so all wiped.
Krish NAik: Yes, how it will come to Nabata? Once you have given, okay, you can pass the exact column names also here. Lalith.
Krish NAik: If you feel that way.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright.
Krish NAik: Now, here, table schema object is created. Now, let's build the vector index of table schemas. Now, I'm creating a vector store index now.
Krish NAik: One by one. So here, I have passed this, table schema object. Okay, and here, to my node mapping, I have passed my actual database. In that database, the tables, so automatically all the tables that will be taken into account. Now, this is the vector embedding that I am creating for my semantic search to take place.
Krish NAik: Alright… This will take some time.
Krish NAik: Now, comms, let's check whether the retrieval works or not. Okay, this is the first step, as you can see, a simple retriever. What is the total revenue? How many customers do we have? So, let's see.
Krish NAik: Alright, for the total revenue.
Krish NAik: If I'm talking about for the total revenue, okay, I can see table 1 retrieved successfully, Table 2, Table 2, Table 1, 2 retrieve. Okay, I can say, yes, the table retrieval is working, because right now, the retrieval happening with respect to the tables.
Krish NAik: Yes, should you also provide foreign key relation? Yes, you can do any type of data relationship. It doesn't really matter. 1 to 1, one-to-many, many-to-one, Arun, all those operations are possible.
Krish NAik: Alright, now comes to your main query definition, the SQL table query engine, okay? Here I have passed So…
Krish NAik: because I know my retriever is working, let's pass the object retriever here, so the table retriever that I have passed it. My main database, which is a SQL database, LLM already I have defined, okay? So, the core initialization I'm doing in the next step.
Krish NAik: Now, let's query across multiple tables. What is the total revenue from all the orders? Okay, let me try to pass this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, table orders has the column ID, so you can actually see the customer ID, product ID, so, actually the context contains order, so that particular context also, you can see. And finally, the predicted SQL, so…
Krish NAik: Right now, select some order total as total revenue from orders.
Krish NAik: Okay, and based on that, the total revenue from all the orders that is coming is close to $565.
Krish NAik: So, separately, you can fire the query to do your manual testing.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you want to manually fire it, so directly you can fire it through Panda SQL, and you can test that part. Okay, I'll say that yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, so customer segmentation, okay, how many customers are there in each region? Alright, let me pass it.
Krish NAik: most of the LLMs Are good at that.
Krish NAik: Right now, any LLMs after 2023, they pretty much support… most of them have the SQL information.
Krish NAik: Okay, so exactly what is SQL? So, based on that, it can generate.
Krish NAik: How to validate the results. If you want to do the validation at any point of time, you can directly use SQL Alchemy, and then you can fire the query
Krish NAik: In both the results, you can check how the results are being shown.
Krish NAik: Alright, then comes…
Krish NAik: Actually… now, if you want to do, evaluation with respect to Ragas, so for those ragas, you have to manually create that.
Krish NAik: Where you'll be, creating… when you'll be creating your evaluation dataset, based on the query the user will be asking, you can keep your original SQL, and then the LLM-generated SQL. In that way, you can actually do the evaluation.
Krish NAik: Alright, so here, based on product reviews, the average is 3.15, that is coming around.
Krish NAik: Then, in the next one, the top 5 best-selling products by quantity sold. Another one, complex query requiring a join operation.
Krish NAik: So, here, this is, you can see, pretty much a complex query.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Mom…
Krish NAik: You can test it out with GPT-5 Nano, and you can actually check the results, like how GPT-5 Nano, because I felt that GPT, in some cases, it makes the error. I know GPT-4, 0, 4.0 Mini, they are at least better in these type of tasks.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a multi-table analysis, which region has generated the most revenue.
Krish NAik: Alright, if you look into the SQL, okay, now, again, yes, this is a bigger SQL, directly on top of customers, orders, okay, and finally getting that information through revenue. I can say that, okay, this is the total, and the most revenue comes from West.
Krish NAik: Will it show us the predicted SQL query every time in the output? Yes, every time. If you don't want that, please change in your setting verbose is equal to false. Okay, I have made in my query somewhere that verbose is equal to true.
Krish NAik: Okay, because of this one, if you want to really… if you… you can make it false if you don't want that, Ariane and others, whoever is asking.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, I think multiple examples I've given for this particular querying.
Krish NAik: Yeah, now,
Krish NAik: Okay, now, the older approach that I have taken, okay, and through this one. Let's try to do the comparison. Okay, now…
Krish NAik: This square engine is different.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this time, let's try to do. Now, okay, this part is an optional part, really, like…
Krish NAik: This is based on Doug DB, but I feel that this part I don't need to be discussed.
Krish NAik: If you guys are interested in DarkTV, you can actually check this part, okay? So, like, if you want to me, I will show you, but really, I don't want to take this part for now. Can you see here? con.execute? What is this?
Krish NAik: What is this, guys?
Krish NAik: a simple SQL query that I can fire.
Krish NAik: Beh.
Krish NAik: Based on the query, the result that I'm getting. Okay, so this is simply…
Krish NAik: On top of the DB that I'm doing.
Krish NAik: And, generally, like, DougDB is good for analytical queries, so I kept few examples, but if you're really interested in
Krish NAik: That one. The idea was to take SQLite, majorly, in the entire thing, I have taken SQLite only. Okay, in some cases, I feel DuckDB is much more powerful.
Krish NAik: Most of the times, I work with Parquet 5CSB, I don't get the information. Parquet is actually that you use it in production. In those cases, very specifically, I feel like TeleDB is much better.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, few things that we have discussed there.
Krish NAik: Okay, now both the engines are cleared to you, and you can start doing your own testing. If you have your own database, please do the test.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then finally, the third is basically the advanced notebook that we have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this one…
Krish NAik: it's a bit, I can say the operations are same, but few workflow operations are there in Llama Index that we'll be talking about.
Krish NAik: Everybody… Just tell me Notebook 1 and Notebook 2, everything is pretty much straightforward that I feel.
Krish NAik: How many of you feel that everything is straightforward?
Krish NAik: It's simple. The query engines are there. If you really work with Langchen, then you will see, because in Langchen, they have a tool-based approach. Okay, so here, actually, there are no external tools that is getting used, so it's pretty much straightforward.
Krish NAik: In the second notebook, yes, you have that SQL table context schema that you can pass, and I feel that, without the context schema, your,
Krish NAik: Like, wrong SQL can be generated. So, the second notebook, I feel, it is powerful as compared to the first one.
Krish NAik: Whenever I am working, at least I'm working with more than 50 to 100 tables. In those cases, I feel having a context schema with respect to every table is much more powerful.
Krish NAik: Alright,
Krish NAik: Let me check whether the third notebook, because this is the advanced one that I have kept it, even, have I executed this notebook previously? I'm not sure about this one.
Krish NAik: Alright, so the OpenAI key, I will write…
Krish NAik: Okay, now, let's take a bigger data set this time, okay? So, I have taken the wikiTable Questions dataset, so you can…
Krish NAik: get this data, okay, and please have a check, because this is a bigger data set till the time that any work that we have done, it's based on some fake data that I was creating, but this time I've actually taken some of the wikiTable questions.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, data set, zip, okay, so… let me see… the zipping operation. It might take, because this is a small download.
Krish NAik: So, everybody please check.
Krish NAik: That this is available or not. At, this will be created, this wikitable questions. Here, you will be having CSV files.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, two, little ones…
Krish NAik: Okay, and really, if you want to know about this, you can go to Wikitable Questions.
Krish NAik: Okay, about this, exactly what is here, the repeatable questions, repeatable questions… On birth control…
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the actual script through which you can actually access it.
Krish NAik: But, this is the main dataset, okay? It's a dataset for a task of question answering on semi-structured HTML databases. Now, that, database that has been created, so there will be a lot of irregularities in some
Krish NAik: columns, some values might be missed. Okay, so the problems will be there, just like the real-time data, because this has been fetched, and based on that, we have taken this data.
Krish NAik: So, and really, there are a lot of columns if you really open it and you try to do an explit. Can you see here, for every HTML file, there is a CSV file and a TSV file?
Krish NAik: Please have a check, guys.
Krish NAik: First of all, always analyze the data set that we are using.
Krish NAik: Chanika, why you will have that? It's for my own context.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, so you can explore the dataset, as simple.
Krish NAik: Now, let's look into… okay, the idea is, load the full wikiTable question dataset with 2,000 plus Wikipedia tables. So, configuration settings, so max table is equal to none, max table is equal to 50, max table is equal to 100.
Krish NAik: So, how much testing you want to do? Simply pass those many tables. I have taken 50.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: I have taken max stability is equal to 50, guys. If you want more, you can pass that.
Krish NAik: Because the total number of tables are really 2,000, so start with a smaller number, you can take lesser numbers.
Krish NAik: Alright, now here, I'm accessing only this folder, the CSV folder. From there, a simple check, whether the directory exists or not, applying glob to fetch out all the CSV files, done.
Krish NAik: Okay, and based on that, I'm just creating a relationship for those 50 tables exactly.
Krish NAik: what will be there? So, here, you can simply look into… so, successfully loaded, 37 tables. Okay, so… average rows per table is close to 30, the total number of rules that you have is close to 118.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in our case, Doha passed 50 tables, but none to load, so exactly we had 37 only. Okay, so it will not fail if you even don't have 50. So in my case, 37s got loaded.
Krish NAik: Please check, guys, this part.
Krish NAik: And a few tables I have ignored, simply. Okay, so here I have kept a failed loot operation. Okay, if there is some column or some value discrimination there, for now, simply, I have skipped them.
Krish NAik: So that's why 37, it came around.
Krish NAik: Please have a check on this one, everybody, and tell me.
Krish NAik: Please have a check, and then let me know. Loading the CSV files.
Krish NAik: Is this part clear or not? Please go through. This is a simple glob operation through which I'm selecting the CSV files based on the condition of 50.
Krish NAik: And there, actually, I'm looking into, like, the idea is to, do, or basically read every CSV, and if you have some bad lines, you can see error bad lines is equal to false data, I have kept it. Simple pandas operation.
Krish NAik: If there are some, simply it will skip them also. So that's why I'm not loading everything. If there are some issues with respect to some tables, simply I have skipped the pure pandas operation.
Krish NAik: Now, extract table names and summaries. So, a simple class that I have created. Okay, if you really look into this as a pydantic table info definition that I have done. Now, generate table summary. Here, we will be actually passing the data frame and the table name, okay? That will be basically a string.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then we'll be looking into some of the sample rows, we'll be looking into the columns.
Krish NAik: And can you see?
Krish NAik: Give me a table with the following structure, provide a short one-sentence, maximum 15 words. You can manipulate this.
Krish NAik: This is a table summary. Table summary means a table context that I am generating using the LLM.
Krish NAik: In the last example, I have manually provided them, but I told you, we'll be using some type of LLM to generate that particular context, okay? Now, this is where this particular implementation comes.
Krish NAik: Okay, this will take some time, as we have a lot of tables, so wait for some time.
Krish NAik: the internet bit actually fluctuates when I switch on the cam, okay? But yes, this will take some time.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please let me know. If you are using different LLMs, in that case, it will be different.
Krish NAik: For me, this is done.
Krish NAik: Took around close to 50 seconds. Please let me know in the chat for everybody, is this part executing?
Krish NAik: This is the call where we are generating the context.
Krish NAik: for each table.
Krish NAik: You can see here, These are some sample table summaries.
Krish NAik: Now, the question comes.
Krish NAik: That, if you have more tables, okay, keep this summary, because right now I have taken smaller, but at least you can increase that. But don't keep a lot of lines. I feel that within 4 to 5 lines, mostly the context that can be defined.
Krish NAik: So, simply, it's true.
Krish NAik: And prompt only that we are generating.
Krish NAik: Now, in the next step, let's do the database setup, okay? I need to create the database engine.
Krish NAik: So, pretty much, I have used SQLite here.
Krish NAik: Okay, creating tables and loading the data.
Krish NAik: Okay, so a simple, few helper functions that I have kept it. Okay, remove special characters and replace spaces with underscores, so a simple sanitization. Create table from data frame, so here, create a table from a Panda's data frame, using SQL alchemy that I have taken.
Krish NAik: These are pure, much more Pandas and SQL… SQL alchemy-based operations.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me take creating 37 database tables.
Krish NAik: Total inserted, estimated time, alright, created.
Krish NAik: 37, okay? In some cases, it has failed, it looked like.
Krish NAik: But, mainly with respect to the creation errors, there is a logic that I have
Krish NAik: Kept, but in our case, it looks like it worked good.
Krish NAik: So, out of 37, 25 got created.
Krish NAik: In some places, there can be some type of discrepancies. Because of that, it is not picked up.
Krish NAik: Please have a check on this one.
Krish NAik: SQLAlchemy! How many of you guys have learned about SQLAlchemy?
Krish NAik: Anybody in Python, everybody teaches about SQL alchemy. When somebody teaches you with respect to SQL, okay? Yes, most of you are, okay, used, used, used. That's why I've taken SQL alchemy also, yes.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine. Now, let's define our vector database.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here I passed my core engine, okay, and then let's look into all the database tables that I have.
Krish NAik: So, all the database table that I have taken into account, okay, and you can see this same function that previously I have used in the first notebook, even in the second notebook, third notebook, everywhere you can actually look into the database tables.
Krish NAik: MSY, because there were some discrepancies, because of that. With respect to the data loading part in Pandas, if something fails, I agree.
Krish NAik: I've taken where all the values are there. If something is missing, I'm not picked up. NA values. MS, that's why.
Krish NAik: Okay, now… This particular approach you guys have already seen.
Krish NAik: So tell me, in the second notebook, this approach I have taken.
Krish NAik: We'll look into the code ones.
Krish NAik: But this time, the context from where I am passing.
Krish NAik: From the generated one. This is to t.table summary, okay, and t.table name that I can access.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that I am accessing things which are generated by the LLM.
Krish NAik: Okay, and finally, let me look into the retrieval output.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: The initialization of the retriever is done. The next step is to actually pass.
Krish NAik: to use that particular retriever to get the object, okay? Now, another helper function that I have, okay, to get the table context, you need the table context, so you can skip some information. As you can see, the table description is, at any point of time, if you feel that you want to add some additional data on top of that.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can pass those information also, or you can skip that, because in my generation, this is how in the form that I have defined it.
Krish NAik: Okay, and finally, through my response, I'll be parsing the entire actual SQL string that will be, getting in the output. So, few helper functions. One is for SQL result parsing, as you can see. So, this, I'll be doing the parsing from the response.
Krish NAik: Okay, then from response through multiple indexing, I'll be getting the actual query.
Krish NAik: So this is a simple parsing operation, you can predict out everything, and based on that, you can look into this helper function exactly.
Krish NAik: Now, text to SQL prompt. Because this is a manual one, just see what is the prompt. So here I pass, given an input question. First, create a syntactically correct engine.dialect.name query to run.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, engine already that I have defined, and specifically, this is just like a placeholder. You can add a print statement to get what is for every, like, dialect.name, it will be specific for your entire data pools.
Krish NAik: Then pay attention to use only the column names that you can see in the schema description. Be careful not to query for columns in this way, this is actually a prompt. Like, every retriever you're using in the prompt. But this time, I'm actually showing you the prompt.
Krish NAik: So, exactly what is going on. So, you are required to use the following format. Question, yeah, then comes your SQL query, SQL result.
Krish NAik: And answered the final answer here.
Krish NAik: Only use tables listed below in the schema. Okay, and finally, the question, the query strain, and based on that, so this is a prompt template that I have defined.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think prompt templates you guys have used in LanChain also, so here also a very similar prompt template that I have taken.
Krish NAik: Okay, now comes your response, prompt, where I'll be actually getting. So, this is your main response type from. Okay, my final answer, how it will look like, so that particular information. And this information is very similar to this, if you really look into.
Krish NAik: Okay, so both the prompt templates, I have defined it.
Krish NAik: is the LLM cal hallucinate. In these type of problems, hallucination is there. This is not really robust. Varna.ai is much more robust, I feel, as compared to text-to-SQL type of task.
Krish NAik: Alright, I'm defining my Pyntic, workflow event here.
Krish NAik: Now…
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is a custom implementation, okay, if you really look into. This is a custom class, text-to-SQL workflow, okay?
Krish NAik: with query time table retrieval. So, query time…
Krish NAik: retrieval, when you look into, it means that an engine that I'll be creating, and that manually I'll be passing. So here, all the things that I've defined. My object retriever, my text-to-SQL prompt, my SQL retriever, response synthesized prompt, and finally the LLM.
Krish NAik: then…
Krish NAik: step by step, because this poor implementation, I have taken it from Lama Index actual, source code, okay? So, def retrieve tables.
Krish NAik: Then comes your next one, which is the generate sequel.
Krish NAik: And generate a response, though I have defined, but for everyone, I need to do the actual function definition. And what will be the output type? The output type here, retrievable, so here, self.
Krish NAik: the context that I'll be getting, EV startup event, so, like, EV data, I've kept it, because here I am using very specific decorators.
Krish NAik: Okay, because these are pure Llama Index crash implementation that I am showing. Okay, so the core implementation that I have taken, directly I'm not taking. I think decorators are much helpful in those cases, otherwise more lines of code that will be added. So, through these decorators, I have done the
Krish NAik: scratch implementation.
Krish NAik: Then comes your, return tables that I have taken here, okay? Then comes generate the, SQL.
Krish NAik: Based on the prompt, based on the query, and the table context, so these are the main parameters for generating the SQL context. Now, this information will go to the LLM. So, here you can see self.lllm.chat format message. This format message
Krish NAik: will go. And then I'm calling the sparse response, because I'll… this sparse response to SQL, and here I am passing the chat response that I'll be getting, so this particular VU. So, step-by-step implementation, because as this is pretty much a custom
Krish NAik: Scratch implementation, you can have a much deeper look. This will take even some time for you to decode exactly what is going on.
Krish NAik: Now, finally, generating the response. Okay, now, generation of the SQL till this point. So, in the next step, generating the response.
Krish NAik: Now, here is the core context that comes, text-to-SQL event, and finally, at this point, your main event will stop, okay? So, your start event happens here.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that step by step, these three functions will be getting executed. So that's why the start event option is there. Okay, here you have a table retriever event, and finally the stop event. So your entire process is done. This is through the definition that I have defined here.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let me run this workflow, because this is a manual engine that I have created. I hope you understand what do I refer via manual engine.
Krish NAik: So this is not a pure Lamai index direct function call, rather than I've defined my own custom logic workflow.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, most of the times in production, you'll be building the complete response logic the way that I have built. This is a pure custom implementation, I feel this is much more powerful, but if you really feel that, you can stick to Notebook 2 implementation. Okay, because it's very, very close.
Krish NAik: The table retriever engine, and this is one.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: How many of you understood exactly what we did? This is a scratch implementation through Lama Intex that I have done.
Krish NAik: Rather than directly using a retrieval engine.
Krish NAik: So, the code that is here, it's actually from the source code of Llama Index that I have taken.
Krish NAik: From the actual class, and then I have built on top of that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so when I send to source code, so every library in GitHub, you can actually check the source code. So, from there only. This is pure custom, and I feel that
Krish NAik: In production, you will be using this particular approach. This gives you much more power as compared to the other approaches. For beginners, it's fine, but later on, always try to
Krish NAik: Create your own custom retrievers.
Krish NAik: Alright, so,
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, like, the year Notorious Big was signed, even, I don't know what is Notorious Big, but in the year 1993, okay, so who was the best director in 1972? Academy Awards?
Krish NAik: Okay, so… based on the table fetch…
Krish NAik: So, you can see, answer assessment, it appears that there were no results found for the best director category in 1972 hours. Therefore, I cannot provide. Can you see here, if there is no such information, it's simply, like, it will fail also?
Krish NAik: Then, which city has the highest population? Let me see here.
Krish NAik: This Wikidata is really old, so don't think about…
Krish NAik: Okay, Goju, Ishunov, alright, based on the data which is available, population of 92.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, the second workflow that I'll be defining… okay, now this is a little bit different. This is a… not only a table retrieval operation, this is table plus row retrieval.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is much more advanced, where you actually pass all your embeddings, like, row by row, embedding creation operation, if you really want to get this one. Okay, because in most of the implementations of VANA AI, we have seen, they use this table plus row retrieval technique.
Krish NAik: Okay, so indexing all table rows.
Krish NAik: In the last time, I was not indexing all the table rules, okay? Pretty much differences are there.
Krish NAik: So here, I have a simple function.
Krish NAik: So, I'm selecting how many rows per table. This you can limit.
Krish NAik: Also, so here, index all tables, I'm passing my main SQL database, table index directory, so this, is the actual string that I'm using to access that. Maximum rules per table, already I have defined this 100, so it's actually 100 here.
Krish NAik: And you can see here, the output type of this particular function is a string with a vector store index object. So here, we'll be indexing all the table rows for our retrieval.
Krish NAik: Now, this approach, when you think that you have millions or trillions of rows in your tables, do you think that this approach is good?
Krish NAik: Because I don't really feel this approach is good in that case.
Krish NAik: Because your vector DB size will increase.
Krish NAik: Okay, and really, like, you'll be paying a lot of money to vector databases. In those cases, really, I don't feel
Krish NAik: Okay, that this is an optimal approach.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, most of the times.
Krish NAik: I've seen that rather than taking all the rules, they will be indexing few rules.
Krish NAik: Okay, and later on, with respect to the context, for better context understanding. Okay, it's a little bit hybrid approach that I'm talking about, but that is much better, rather than doing this operation.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the index table, and later on, I'll be using this particular function to define this. Now, this is a pretty much big function that I have taken. Okay, so here I have defined all those things, then I'll be looking into whether the table index directory exists or not. Okay, then vector store index, then I'm defining my main SQL,
Krish NAik: Alchemy Engine, okay, getting usable table names, all those information, and then step-by-step one, I'm accessing each one, and then from there.
Krish NAik: So here, this limit operation that I have applied, you can see, maximum rules per table. So, select star from, what it will return.
Krish NAik: When I do select star from table lamp limit.
Krish NAik: This will provide me those accessible rows, the max one that I have defined here, because this becomes the limit.
Krish NAik: Okay, that I have passed in. So, simply, I'm firing up an SQL query, and based on that, I'm fetching up the results. Through that, I can access. And now, once I have the access to those 100 rows, I'm creating text node. Okay, because in Llama index, okay, so nodes, or basically, you can think about chance.
Krish NAik: Okay, in simple terms, nodes refer to chunks in Lama Index. So, I'm just creating text nodes on top of each root up that I am getting. So, here, a simple check, escape whether there are empty tables or not. And finally, I am passing those nodes, or basically chunks you can think about, to our vector store index.
Krish NAik: Now, if you want to save them as a persistent storage, so I have kept all those options. Really, you can check into the implementation.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this will take some time, so let's wait.
Krish NAik: Alright, so looks like 37 tables, and the total number of rows which are indexed are 66.
Krish NAik: Alright, now defining our custom retriever again.
Krish NAik: Okay, so def, get table context with rows.
Krish NAik: So here are the things that I'm passing, my main query string, within comes the table schema object, and finally, reverse boolean that I've kept it a false, you can make it true later on if you want all the, results from there.
Krish NAik: Now, from table schema object, in table schema, so the idea is to access
Krish NAik: All the rows to SQL database get single table info, so from here, I'm getting the access to all the tables one by one, because it is inside a for loop. Then I'm looking into the string object, so the context that I have previously created, the table description is…
Krish NAik: Okay, and on top of that, you can actually generate the context. So, in your main, chunk information, okay, you can keep this particular also, like, in every chunk.
Krish NAik: That is referred to as a little bit contextual retrieval, but that approach also works really good. So here, I have taken, simply, and based on that, I am accessing the context string. Okay, and finally, my core context with respect to the row indexes now are available. Now come to my
Krish NAik: main, retriever object, so here I've defined my vector index, table schema.object.table name, as retriever. Okay, so here I'll be accessing only the rows and nothing much more.
Krish NAik: Then, my main vector store inter .retrieve, and I am passing my query string.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, based on that, so here, of certain logic, if you don't have any nodes only, nothing you can do.
Krish NAik: Because at the end of the day, you need nodes. Without the notes, you cannot do the processing, so simply… and give an else statement logic that I have kept. Otherwise, it will simply print out the information if verbose is equal to true. You will be getting that table info. Okay, so by default, it is false.
Krish NAik: But if you want the table information, you can keep it as true.
Krish NAik: So this function I have defined, now…
Krish NAik: This is a next class definition that I have passed, because this, retrieval engine directly, I'll be calling it here. So here, step…
Krish NAik: So, first of all, I need to retrieve the table, and if you see the return type here, okay, so here we'll be actually getting the table information, the core table info from this particular function.
Krish NAik: So, here we are getting the retrieve tables, here we'll be passing the context, this is a startup event, okay, because as this is the first one, and then we will be triggering the table retrieve event. The return type is table retrieve. It means that it will only retrieve your main table, which is required.
Krish NAik: Okay, and inside that, I'm passing my table schema object and table context also, that I've generated using the prompt through the LLM.
Krish NAik: This is another workaround, really. Like, these are pretty much custom implementations. If you really feel this can be helpful.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can really test it out based on your work. So, right here, the table info that I'm getting, okay, so here, verbose is equal to true that I have done, so you'll be, getting both the information with row retrieval, alright, big 19935.
Krish NAik: Okay, can you see that the row information is also… it's showing me?
Krish NAik: from exactly.
Krish NAik: The table is T14.
Krish NAik: And it's telling you this is the exact entry that you have.
Krish NAik: Guys, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Because previously, this… because, see, at the end of the day, whenever we are working with AI, explainability is one of the main things, and here, things really can be explained.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I've taken that particular example.
Krish NAik: Okay, and really was signed to Bad Boy in 1993, alright. From here, finally, how the result looked like.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, these are some, in-project IPUs, like, if you want to really do a validation that validates the SQL query for SEPT, so a few other implementation and workflows, I have kept it, but you can test it out.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this approach is a little bit advanced, but I will say that, because even I have taken the implementation from the poor Llama Index modules only, but I feel that if you want to really create your own custom retrievers, you can pick up, like, Workflow 1, Workflow 2. These are a few example workflows I have provided.
Krish NAik: because these libraries don't have very highly optimized to perform text-to-SQL tasks, but I feel going forward, like, tomorrow, I'll be talking about VANA setup, so there…
Krish NAik: It's much better, okay? Because VANA is much better for these type of tasks, at least as compared to. Because most of the solutions that I've looked into in others, project and repose.
Krish NAik: they create a pretty much hybrid approach. Few things from Llama, a few things from Langchain, and then they try to build their text-to-SQL approach.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this part is also done, majorly I've gone through, but this part is hard, okay? Remember…
Krish NAik: That's why I've kept it beginner, intermediate, and advanced.
Krish NAik: Advance is really… this part is hard. It means that you need to spend more than 2 to 3 hours. The entire approach that I have done.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Alright, now for tomorrow's class. It's…
Krish NAik: Because I think, finally, the fourth notebook is there, which we'll be discussing.
Krish NAik: the post-grace one, okay? So, this is a simple connection notebook, okay? So, please create your Superbase accounts, because for your project discussion, it is required, so tomorrow I won't be doing it. Please do the setup today only.
Krish NAik: Okay? Just open up Superbase, and create your account.
Krish NAik: Execution take 2-3 hours, but creating the notebook can take 2 to 3.
Krish NAik: Yes, it takes for me, because, sometimes I need to convert the scripts into notebook. That becomes a problem for me also, because most of the things are in script, so that particular conversion, exactly, I have to look into.
Krish NAik: That, because Fuse… most of the implementations I have taken for the core Lama Index.
Krish NAik: Package only.
Krish NAik: Okay, and based on that. So, everybody, please create your Superbase accounts, because going forward in your project also, Superbase, okay? So, Super Base. Everybody knows about Superbase.com. Is there anybody who doesn't know about Superbase?
Krish NAik: I'll leave it. Okay, so… Let's see, I'm not on which one? Okay, let me go into this one.
Krish NAik: Oh, release.
Krish NAik: In this account, I don't have a superbase, so I think…
Krish NAik: Start your project. You can click on start your project.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then you can do, continue with GitHub, or whichever, okay, so create your own account. Whichever way you like it, please do that.
Krish NAik: SK, can you share how do you create the notebook?
Krish NAik: I create the notebooks by taking the core package, Lama Index later, there I look into the core module, and based on that, I bring the scripts, and then…
Krish NAik: Alright, so people are asking, what is Superbase? So, this is a Postgres-hosted service.
Krish NAik: Okay, so simply, like, Postgres database that you have in the cloud.
Krish NAik: Moait Bisaria. You guys don't know about… the idea is to work with postgrace? Okay, so that's why I picked up Supervis.
Krish NAik: We are not done for today.
Krish NAik: Why will be done? Everybody, please create your account. Once you have created your account, okay, from here you can do a sign-up, you can see. If you want to continue with GitHub, or you want to do the sign-up in whichever way, please do the sign-up.
Krish NAik: Once your accounts are created, okay, please have a check on that.
Krish NAik: Because, this…
Krish NAik: But what? Created account? Everybody created account? Then just create a project.
Krish NAik: Yeah, because if I pass it here, okay, this is my other one.
Krish NAik: Nate, let me just sign up here also.
Krish NAik: This account failed to sign up part 1… And…
Krish NAik: And even sign up, okay? But then leave it. So, you will be looking into something like this.
Krish NAik: Okay, you will be having, this particular information. Okay, about, in my case, you can see here, but the main thing is you need the SQL editor.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this is the query, to create the tables. Okay, so please…
Krish NAik: get… because this is the first part, I think in your case, you will be having, by default, the default one. So there, we'll be getting the option of string. So, please get this string, and put it in your .env file.
Krish NAik: Everybody. This is very, very important because this is the connection string through which you'll be accessing the SuperViz Cloud.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everybody please get this information. In my case, if I show you.
Krish NAik: Okay, canceled.
Krish NAik: I think if I show you my envy, okay, in my place.
Krish NAik: I think somewhere I have pasted it.
Krish NAik: Option 1v2.
Krish NAik: Okay, so actually, I'm sharing you my information, exactly the things that I have done.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you really feel like, once you have the connection string, from the connection string, you can actually decode it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for example, I told you, copy this string. See, step by step, I am doing everybody follow. Copy this one, okay? Once you have copied it, just paste it below, okay? For your own reference, just put a comment. And from here, you can actually pass the information that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can see most of the things here, but you can actually, update that. Like, this particular information, db. So, this is the only thing that you need to put it here. For example, here, under your… this host.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in this way, please update. What is the port? Port number is 5432, please update that. The user will be Postgres, by default. In my case. The Postgres DB will also be Postgres, and then comes your Superbase password. Okay, so whatever the password that you have kept it. Please do the configuration, everybody.
Krish NAik: From your side.
Krish NAik: So, please take the connection string, and then you have to do it. Okay? Again, I'm showing it. So, in your case, whenever you open, so it will be looking something like this, okay? Once you have created your account, there will be a default one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so simply, if I show you… okay, so let me just create a new project. Okay, organization is fine, project name is, Paul Text2SQL.
Krish NAik: Okay, our database password is needed. Okay, use a strong password. I will copy this one, ACF Pacific.
Krish NAik: Okay, everybody, please create a new project, first of all. The way that I have created, simply create a new one, or I think for everybody, there will be a default one. You can use the default one also.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is… politics to SQL is done.
Krish NAik: Okay, and that particular, whatever the password was there, okay, I will keep it.
Krish NAik: Somewhere in comment later on, I can use it a bit, so… Now, what I will do, I have to update my ENV file.
Krish NAik: So, my.env.
Krish NAik: Here. Okay, so… OpenAI API key, I don't need to change. OpenAI model, text embeddings 3 is small. Now, this is a part that I need to update.
Krish NAik: Okay, so what I will do, I will just copy all this stuff, let me just, bring it here.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I will just comment all this for now. This is the actual DB.
Krish NAik: Now, I told you, get the connection string.
Krish NAik: So, once you have this one, so you can actually go to your table editor, or you can actually click on this connect option.
Krish NAik: Okay, from your connect option, you will see that you will be having this…
Krish NAik: Okay? You have to just copy this. There is a clipboard option.
Krish NAik: And paste it here.
Krish NAik: I brought it here.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, see, this part, if I try to remove it completely, let me remove it. Okay, so this part, I can actually copy it from here.
Krish NAik: tail.goo.
Krish NAik: Actually, I've not used the complete DB string, okay, rather than I have kept it in this way.
Krish NAik: Okay, and finally comes our… My badge, I think that I can access it through
Krish NAik: This password. Alright, I have done all the configuration, guys, see?
Krish NAik: Please do the configuration by yourself.
Krish NAik: Once the configuration is done, I think I have a test Supervis connection file. This you can actually run to check that the connection is successful or not.
Krish NAik: Okay? Because even I plated it manually. So please just be sure you take care of this.
Krish NAik: like, environment variables that you have. Your host, you will be getting from here only, from DB to this one. Port 5432. Postgres user, by default, it is, like, the Postgres one only, and Postgres, I think. Majorly, this is done.
Krish NAik: Yes, these are the default ones. Nothing you have to change. Now, this tailway super connection is there. Okay, this script, you can actually run it if you feel. So, for example, if I open my terminal…
Krish NAik: Okay, so I can run this one.
Krish NAik: UV run… Alright, turn, the name of the file is test… supervisconnection.py.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can see here, connection successful, postgrave version 17.6, no table files, and yes, right now there are no tables for sure, but the superbase connection is ready.
Krish NAik: Guys, please tell me… a simple process. I don't think the process is so much complicated.
Krish NAik: How to get the host name? Somebody's asking.
Krish NAik: Alrighty.
Krish NAik: See, this is my main ENV file.
Krish NAik: Host name is there in the main connection link only. When you get the connection string, there only you have the name of host.
Krish NAik: db.whatever, in your case, it will be different, okay? In my case, I have just shown you. This part, exactly, you need to keep it in host.
Krish NAik: And the port. Sometimes the port can be different, okay? But, majorly, all of the settings. Now, the password that you have actually created, that I have passed. I've just shown you exactly everything from scratch. So, everybody, please let me know that, whether the connection is successful, for how many of you?
Krish NAik: Naga is asking, where is the connection string? So, what I am showing so many times, whenever you have this, just click on this connect button, and you will be getting your connection string.
Krish NAik: This is your connection string, you need to just copy it, and keep it in your .env file. Please, everybody, have a check.
Krish NAik: Because in our project, I will be using Superbase only, that's why.
Krish NAik: Please, let me know, guys.
Krish NAik: For how many of you the connection is successful.
Krish NAik: I'm not in a hurry, plus do the connection, this connection is important. In your project, this connection you guys will be doing, that's why.
Krish NAik: Please go back to the SuperBase site. Yes, this is the SuperBase site, I have gone back.
Krish NAik: Mammoth successful. Alright. What about others? Arun, connected too? Alright, Mammoth done. Ankit, Mode, able to connect. Dan, Ravi. Great. It's easy only, I don't think it's tough.
Krish NAik: It's just… you need to figure it out, this particular… once you have this string, then the rest of the things… that's why I've taken a simple example.
Krish NAik: Okay, so take the string, and then break it down. What is the host? This is the host. Okay, then comes your port, then comes your user, okay, and initially your DB. So that slash last end, everything, I have kept it in one place.
Krish NAik: By default, the user is Postgres only. Later on, you can create a user, you can do those DB-based operations, just like Postgres. But right now, I'm just simply showing you how to connect with Postgres.
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Yes, you can create a project, delete a project, whatever you want to do, there is no restriction.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, guys, everyone.
Krish NAik: For everybody, the connection should be successful.
Krish NAik: Please run the script just like me, okay, I have executed, you will see connection successful, otherwise simply will get an error.
Krish NAik: Okay, as simple as that.
Krish NAik: Okay? As simple as that. So this is just a test file that I have created, just to show you the connection. Alright.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, can we proceed to the next step, or should I wait for 2 minutes more?
Krish NAik: Okay, people are telling, wait, alright, fine, do the configuration.
Krish NAik: In the next step, I'll be just creating the table, nothing more.
Krish NAik: This is the ENV file config.
Krish NAik: Get your connection string and pass the information.
Krish NAik: How many of you have previously used Superbase?
Krish NAik: Rahul Parir past the credentials, otherwise nothing will work.
Krish NAik: In the error only, it's telling me…
Krish NAik: Yes, username is Postgres.
Krish NAik: Salty of energy check, there is some connection issue.
Krish NAik: Because this script is your helper script, otherwise I do have another script also, that also you can test, but not in this repo, I have that script. Where you can parse the entire DB string only, the entire connection string, then it will parse, then it will do.
Krish NAik: That is the other way around, but I think it should work majorly for everybody, it's working, only
Krish NAik: Like, Poonam, if there is some issue with your Pi SG, because right now the driver that I am using, if there is an issue with the package, you will get an error. So have a check according to your system. This package. This is the main package, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, the PostgreSQL driver. If there is some issue with the package, you'll be getting an error, so please have it checked your package dependency.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine.
Krish NAik: I've waited 2 minutes, I think now I can proceed.
Krish NAik: You cannot look at the connection string, it's on the top only, no? Connections thing here, connect button is there. Should I zoom into the page much more?
Krish NAik: See here, you have on-top connection.
Krish NAik: Okay, so directly from here, you'll be getting your connection string, as simple, you just need to copy this connection string.
Krish NAik: None.
Krish NAik: Alright, I've zoomed really a lot, now I'll just do a reset.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now when I go to my… I will now move to the next step. I assume for most of you it's done.
Krish NAik: Yes, you can go, you can look into the parameters and others also.
Krish NAik: Now, first of all, right now, I don't have tables. So, for generating tables, what I need to define?
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: Here, all the editors are there, you can actually check this part. Whoever is asking how you can do.
Krish NAik: Okay, please check. Table Editor is there, SQL editor is there.
Krish NAik: Alright, now I think in my other project, I already have that.
Krish NAik: Somewhere around, this creation, I projected it. I'll be taking a schema as simple as that. I think in my SQL editor, it's already there, okay? So let me just copy this entire one there. Okay, I'll be sharing with you this, I don't think you guys have this one. I'll be pasting it in Notion, okay? Just wait.
Krish NAik: You can, take it from here.
Krish NAik: Text goes 3 equal…
Krish NAik: Even I provide you that .sql file, you can check that. From there, also, you can generate. So that particular sample I provided in the repo, please have it checked. Okay, otherwise, please look into this one. This is SQL SQL, yeah, alright.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the main one, I've shared it in Notion. Otherwise, in your repo of your Advanced Act tutorial.
Krish NAik: Okay, not in advanced, right? Where is that text to SQL here? I have given you the setup, SQL-based schema. You can use this schema also, or the one that I have shared, okay, in Notion, whichever way that you want to do it.
Krish NAik: So, what I will do, I will go inside this, Paul Text2SQL, I will go to the SQL editor, and I will paste this schema that I have copied, okay? And then I will run the query. As simple as that.
Krish NAik: I copied the schema.
Krish NAik: into the SQL editor, because right now, I don't have tables only, so what I will do in the table editor? Nothing I can do. So I'm… I have gone into the SQL editor, I copied this particular schema, and then I have simply done a run operation. Okay, I have had the query. Okay, let me click on run, run this query, fine.
Krish NAik: Everybody take the schema from Notion or from the file, whichever way you are comfortable.
Krish NAik: In Notion, also, I have pasted the one that I have taken, or the one that's from the script.
Krish NAik: I think both can be a little bit different, but they will achieve the same functionality. Okay, so can you see here, based on the tables that I have created, alright, I can see my privacy schema, alright, this got created. Now, if I look into the table editor.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… can you see? The tables got created, customer order summary, customer's orders. So just be sure you copy the schema, and you get it. 4 tables are created, alright, Ankush, correct?
Krish NAik: Actually, 3 tables are there, one is a view. This is view, okay? These are… see, these are 3 tables, but one is a view.
Krish NAik: Okay, so don't get confused that 4 tables are there. There are actually 3 tables.
Krish NAik: Srinivas, just check the script that I have taken it into Notion, the same script I have pasted it here. Please let me know, because, guys, I've not really tested, that, SQL one.
Krish NAik: Connection not working, MS,
Krish NAik: why… so why saying download CSV and not able to see the table? Why it's saying download CSV?
Krish NAik: Where download CSV is coming.
Krish NAik: Because right now, I'm not doing anything here, okay? If you want, I can create a new file, and I will paste it, okay? So, just wait.
Krish NAik: This is Text2SQL… Okay.
Krish NAik: Because I think this is the same schema.
Krish NAik: But, okay, alright, okay, schema added…
Krish NAik: Cancel…
Krish NAik: The exact one in both the places I am sharing, in whichever way you want to access it, please access it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so take it from the GitHub, everything I have pasted it.
Krish NAik: You can do anything. Right now, don't focus on formatting and other things.
Krish NAik: It's totally based on that, that's why I've kept comment very specifically.
Krish NAik: Alright, this is the schema that is created. Now the question comes, how to populate the data?
Krish NAik: Okay, because the next step is the data population, because right now, if I click on this table, the table is empty. You can import it from a CSV file, you can do drag and drop a CSV file here.
Krish NAik: This option is there in Superbase, okay, but I will be using a script.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think with respect to my script, okay, my text to SQL, wikiTables, I do have a script here.
Krish NAik: create sample tables, I think, yes, this is the one. Alright, yes, this is a custom data script that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this script, I will just execute it. Okay, now, using this script, I'm just generating the data, and it will be uploaded into tables. As simple as that. You can see here, I'm making a connection to the Superbase engine, and then one by one, I will simply execute all the tables, query, and everything.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, using this simple script.
Krish NAik: you can actually do the insertion, I think UV run.
Krish NAik: Paul added the written organization. Yes, Superbase… Superbase is a very famous product, yes, and Superbase, they do use.
Krish NAik: Like, in production, people are using super-based, and these type of operations are pretty much common in any type of SQL-based task.
Krish NAik: Okay, UV, brown… Python, the name of the file is CreateSample Tables.
Krish NAik: Okay, so…
Krish NAik: how… please tell me, guys, that tables are created, then only the script will work. Otherwise, if the tables are not created, the script won't work.
Krish NAik: Please let me know. For everybody.
Krish NAik: For how many of you the tables are created, please let me know with a yes, yes, or no in the chat.
Krish NAik: Yes? Okay, everybody, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, run the data population, alright. Now, see, this script that I have taken, UV run python create sample tables, so this is the file that I'm actually executing.
Krish NAik: I've taken a batch, okay, and finally.
Krish NAik: This is executed, okay? Now, just give it some second, it will take some time. Let me just close the view.
Krish NAik: Can you see? The data that I have pushed is successfully now uploaded here?
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: For everybody, please. It takes some time, 10 to 15 seconds, okay, to reflect the results, but it will show.
Krish NAik: people who are getting, please check your Pi SYG driver, okay? Don't say that you are getting that error. The error comes due to driver. You need to check the driver is according to your system, like Windows or Mac, okay? So please have a check on that.
Krish NAik: The tables got the data. Similarly, you can check your order tables.
Krish NAik: Okay, order also I have… And customers also.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it takes some time, so just be sure to check in, like, 15 seconds, 20 seconds, or all the tables, I have populated the data.
Krish NAik: And simply, I can run any operation as simple as that. Because the same task that I will be doing, in our project also.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why this particular approach, I'm making it familiar to everyone, so that you guys know how to connect with a superbase.
Krish NAik: Once you have connected with the superbase, then what is the next thing?
Krish NAik: What is the next thing?
Krish NAik: Once you have connected with the superbase, the next thing is, create the schema.
Krish NAik: Okay, once the schema is done, from those schema, your empty tables will be created. Once your empty tables are created, then run the script. It will populate the data from your local machine. Okay? Create the schema and insert the rules, correct.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the flow that even in our project that I'll be doing, so always remember that part.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, if you really check with the notebook 4,
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is a notebook 4 that I have, so I will just close all these connections, okay?
Krish NAik: Let me just kill all those operations in file.
Krish NAik: SQL sample test, okay?
Krish NAik: Now, this notebook is purely just to do the connection setup, and nothing more than this notebook, because the core implementations part I have already shown you.
Krish NAik: Okay, DB45 through, environment variables loaded. Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Okay, the connection to Postgres is successful. Then comes query discovery and inspection, so this is the next part. So previously, I've taken SQLite. Okay, so in this example, I've taken that separate orders where, like, here, the engine is different. You have to understand, the database is different.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, these are some examples of Postgres that I have kept it, so simple SQL operations, because this is a simple print statement that I have kept, just for beginners.
Krish NAik: Then I can define my LLM, and you can see here, I've taken the example just to show you. I've picked up that NL SQL. I've not passed any context or anything for now, but based on that, you can actually check that the connection is working or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, so there are total 500 customers in the data. I know that this is correct. Okay, so a sample query that I've fired. I think here, a few more queries are there, whichever you want to apply, you can check that out.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just have a check that everything is working fine or not.
Krish NAik: In this particular notebook, everything should be executing.
Krish NAik: Because here, it's the same Notebook 1 only, but I have only changed the… data base.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a cloud-hosted, proper Postgres SQL engine. That's the only thing.
Krish NAik: Because even Subhash, really, like, in my case, it worked, even I'm not sure. Everybody, please check, this part. This part should be working, because there is nothing that I have done. Okay, it's purely notebook one execution that I have just executed. Only the database I have changed.
Krish NAik: Rest, everything is… the same thing.
Krish NAik: It's actually Notebook 1, only the database part is done. Because going forward, even for VANA.ai, I think tomorrow… okay, how much time we have today? It's 12.3.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, we can discuss today also.
Krish NAik: We have time.
Krish NAik: Okay, created the schema, then ingested the data. Okay, it's 1221, and my system, it's telling 12.3. Okay, 1220. Fine, fine, fine, fine, it's updated. Fine, tomorrow only we'll do, don't worry.
Krish NAik: Thank you.
Krish NAik: Now, alright, fine, this part is done. Everybody, please spend more time on this. Okay, do more research, I can say. Really, like, text-to-SQL, this is an optional thing that comes from the RAG, but in some cases, I feel that, yes, this is a powerful system, okay, so…
Krish NAik: Now, coming to tomorrow's discussion, exactly what I'll be doing. So, if you have time, please do the setup beforehand.
Krish NAik: Because the same setup that I'll be doing, tomorrow also you can do. So, I'll be changing the repo, but at least I won't be changing a lot of things, okay? So, this is for tomorrow's discussion. Exactly what are the things that I'll be telling, okay? So, let me just check here one thing, just wait.
Krish NAik: I'll create the lambda function.
Krish NAik: Hmm… not right.
Krish NAik: Function, status, ERM, alright. Because actually, I was working with ERM-based images, it took me a lot of time to do.
Krish NAik: Okay, because ERM images are much faster than Lambda. So, this is our next project, the multidata Rack project. Okay, so here,
Krish NAik: Similarly, like, if you want to do this,
Krish NAik: connection with respect to, your… what I can say.
Krish NAik: Superbase setup. Okay, so create a dedicated new project in Superbase. You have the script here, superbasecontest.py. Using this you can do. Now, this is a direct connection string script that I have kept it, okay? If you want, you can see this is a much smaller script.
Krish NAik: But directly using PYIG, you can do this also. Okay, now this is the other way.
Krish NAik: of doing the test. First, I always shoot bigger, and then I will come to the easier one. Okay? Now, then, I think you, I have given you somewhere
Krish NAik: Sample data, okay, that sample data, I have not provided to you.
Krish NAik: Let me just check data. Okay, here, inside the data, you have generate sample query. Okay, so please execute the script, and generate your data.
Krish NAik: Okay, keep it configured for tomorrow's class. Again, I am repeating. For tomorrow's project, what I'll be doing, I will be using this generate sample data, okay? So, please use the script which is available under the data folder.
Krish NAik: Okay, the schema script, I have not kept it, it looks like. Alright, fine. I'll be providing the schema. I think the SQL file, I have not uploaded that. Okay, I will… okay, here you have schema.sql.
Krish NAik: Please, that's why I thought I will be keeping it. Please check. Whoever is asking, Ankit, okay?
Krish NAik: It's in my GitHub that directly pick up from my GitHub.
Krish NAik: Okay? Alright. Now, everybody, just be sure tomorrow don't spend time on this.
Krish NAik: Again, I'm repeating myself.
Krish NAik: Okay, I'm sharing the link. Please do the configuration of SuperBase directly, so that I can start with the integration. In the meantime, you can, if you want to really look into the notebook that I'll be discussing, this is the notebook. Only a single notebook for VANA.
Krish NAik: Because to discuss VANA, there are a lot of other things, but I will just stick to my main core objective, which is text-to-SQL. Otherwise, VANA, that comes totally as a separate service only.
Krish NAik: Okay, this notebook, you guys can explore all the things. So, this is a pretty much, like, a starter notebook. Okay, and you can just go through the notebook exactly what other things are there. It's much easy. This is agentic architecture. Okay, so everything is pretty much easy to work with.
Krish NAik: And, one of the best things that I love about this one is, can you say your schema context? You can actually pass your entire database schema.
Krish NAik: this particular thing, really, I feel helpful. Okay, so… and you can create relationships, a lot of other things that you can do, because this is much more advanced. But I will give you the basics, and then I will directly do the integration.
Krish NAik: Alright, this is the core part, so if you have time, because tomorrow we'll be discussing the notebook for sure. Okay.
Krish NAik: And, lot of other things are there in the, repo there, but,
Krish NAik: Yes, Amherst universe, you have to provide examples if you do the identification of multiple relationships in that way.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is one, because even I've not tested.
Krish NAik: And, just remember, the deployment takes a lot of time, because right now, I'm just showing you a sample, it will take close to 23… like, 24 minutes, okay? Because here I have used a lot of ERM-only based images, I have not used any x64, so pretty much a bigger deployment, you can look into all the files are there.
Krish NAik: I have pretty much cleaned the report.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now this is the same thing that we'll be doing tomorrow.
Krish NAik: Yes, using Langraph also you can do it, there is no restriction in that. Okay, let me just check that part, because I don't remember.
Krish NAik: the URL ones. This is a test deployment.
Krish NAik: Okay, the entire health deployment is not there.
Krish NAik: Well, they are in 64.
Krish NAik: Mmm, just wait once.
Krish NAik: Okay, let me even… I don't remember that.
Krish NAik: Where is this one? Command Y?
Krish NAik: Hmm…
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, because this is how your main, will look like, okay, in the project, okay? I have added, like, for now, I've taken a simple fraud server only.
Krish NAik: Okay, health, is there, okay, so… This is completely based on Lambda, the entire application is on Lambda, so it's not a permanent storage, every 10 to 15 minutes, it will be there.
Krish NAik: doc rack, query routing, all right. Even the README file is not updated, but,
Krish NAik: Because I started the class with respect to your deployment, and then, actually, I tested it out a bit. So, Phase 1, Phase 3, Phase 6, Docker deployment is done.
Krish NAik: Here's some stats…
Krish NAik: This time, I'll be using Pinecone. In the meantime, if you want, please, create a Pinecone account. Okay, those things, you can do the setup. It's easy, but beforehand, if you take care, okay, please create your own Pinecone accounts. Everybody.
Krish NAik: Okay, let me just say,
Krish NAik: a query sample, okay? So… yeah, because I've not tested any APIs, but
Krish NAik: let me see whether it works or not. Because I think the deployment part will start, next week.
Krish NAik: Sulvana…
Krish NAik: Issues, multi-data, notebooks…
Krish NAik: Because this time, the deployment is a little bit tougher. A lot of other things that needs to be taken care of.
Krish NAik: Okay, so what is the total revenue from orders? Let me just copy this, and I will actually test it out.
Krish NAik: Whether it works or not.
Krish NAik: So, tomorrow, everybody, please do the setup of Superbase and create your own Pinecone accounts, okay? Pinecone is completely free, okay? Just go to Pinecone, do a simple setup, and get the API key. As simple as that.
Krish NAik: Okay, everybody, please, take care of that.
Krish NAik: Okay? Alright, fine.
Krish NAik: So, like, I was actually testing the system as this is pretty much Lambda, and based on Lambda, I've kept everything. My main ingestion was based on that Understanding Climate PDF that I have taken.
Krish NAik: But, this is a pending approval, okay? Like, I have taken a system that not directly, it means that you have to take the query ID, okay? If you want actually to execute that query, then you can actually go here.
Krish NAik: And, you can do a list of pending, okay? So here, you will see that, okay, this query is pending. So in that way, I've given approval. It means that in production systems, it's a bad thing that anybody can do anything. That's why I've taken the decision of taking a stepwise. It means that
Krish NAik: directly, nobody can do that. Once the SQL is getting generated, then if you want to fire that, you need an approval.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why you can see pending approval, I've created a route, pending, and then really, if you want to execute that, query, then you can go here, you can paste out the query ID.
Krish NAik: Okay, so few things I have taken, I think.
Krish NAik: Like, if you find it interesting, because this is actually in production, how it works. So, here, from there, like, any result that you'll be getting from there, based on the query. So, multiple level of orders that I have taken.
Krish NAik: And I feel that this is… and this time, even, I've taken a little bit things with respect to catch yours.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you get the same document, then it will detect
Krish NAik: Embedded catch also I've taken into account, so this project is more complex as compared to the others.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think then for today, I'm pretty much done. Okay, so just be sure, create your Pinecone account.
Krish NAik: Okay, and in the entire thing, I'll be using OpenAI only, so nothing to worry about. OpenAI key, I will be using, but if you want to do the configuration with any others, you can do the selection.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, few things that I have taken. I think the rest, we are good, okay?
Krish NAik: nothing more to discuss today, then I can take some questions. In the meantime, you guys can let me know anything is there in the chat or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's start with Mitesh, Unam… Imran…
Krish NAik: Just wait, guys, let me check the headphone is correctly attached or not.
Krish NAik: Yes, I think, please try to say something, anybody.
Mitesh Shah: Nitesh?
Mitesh Shah: I'm audible.
Krish NAik: Your voice is low, I don't know from my side it is low. Okay, just repeat yourself once again.
Mitesh Shah: Am I ain'.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes.
Krish NAik: Your voice is low. Others are also confirming.
Mitesh Shah: Thank you.
Krish NAik: Okay, just check in the meantime. Yes, in the meantime, US guys, let's take Rahul, then you have Ravi USA,
Krish NAik: Okay.
Rahul Parihar: Hey, Paul, can I share my screen? So… I was able to establish the connection? Yeah, just thanks.
Krish NAik: Alright, I will add you to panelist.
Ravi USA: Yeah, okay.
Krish NAik: Then, I think next, Ravi?
Ravi USA: Yeah, so I have a few questions, actually. Like, yeah, actually, I joined, like, just, this week. I have to check some other recordings from previous weeks also, but I have some…
Krish NAik: from older batches, so, like, for you, transition is really easy, see here. Till now, in the course only, I've discussed LangChain, Llama Index, and a little bit of text-to-SQL that I have started, few things with respect to…
Krish NAik: hybrid approaches, few things, but all basic or prep. It's not, like, very hard stuff.
Ravi USA: Yeah, yeah, definitely. Yeah, sure. So, few things I'm looking for is, first thing, like,
Ravi USA: this, the NL SQL table query engine and all these things, or even the, the last access that you have shown, like, from using the Postgres SQL. So, can it be even applied on Databricks tables, Delta tables, those kind of things? Do we have connectors for that, or this is only.
Krish NAik: Yes, connectors are available in Databricks.
Ravi USA: Okay, so even if we have.
Krish NAik: And Databix connectors are available in Langchain as well as Elamindex, so you can, yes, you can work with them.
Krish NAik: Okay. Here you can work with Dynamo tables from AWS, Cosmos, RDS, everything. Those things can come.
Krish NAik: No issues.
Ravi USA: Okay, yeah, and like, when I'm seeing this, this, like, these sequels that are generated, I don't see any primary case or foreign keys that were specified explicitly, but still the system is able to identify it properly. So, like, is there any, like, hallucinations possible there, or, so, like, what are the prerequisite metadata that we need?
Ravi USA: For the sequels to be more accurate.
Krish NAik: Generally, it's a good practice to keep that particular, like, primary key directly in your context, and that primary key is how related to the other tables also. You can create a relationship and keep it in that particular context.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in vana.ai, generally we keep it in the context only. That is better, always. And all the relationship from your pyramid to the other tables also. So all those things, you need to maintain it in your main context schema.
Ravi USA: Okay, okay. And also, like, the column description, like, these are just a few examples that we are seeing here, but when we want to use this for, our own domain-specific use cases in companies, so this… there are, like, 50 or 100 tables.
Ravi USA: They're in the snowflake schema, or star schema, something like that, and also the… each of the tables
Ravi USA: I mean, they're joined different… and there is some specific domain technology and everything that they have. Like, in that kind of a situation where the domain expert… I mean, like, a business user is actually using this to generate a SQL, like, replacing a BA developer or something like that, a BA report or something like that. So, can it be scaled to that level?
Ravi USA: And also, like, if that is the case, so how can we make this… that these LLMs understand.
Krish NAik: You have to create your own custom workflow, the way that I have shown in the third notebook. That is how you actually do. You have to define every time the default retrievers won't work for you. For your own one, you have to create. That's why I showed you the custom one.
Krish NAik: by reading a simple CSV, or by reading… so, for example, if you have anything in Snowflake, by using, like, packages are there for Snowflake data reading also that you can do, create a connection, get the data, you can create your own retriever.
Krish NAik: That's the V.
Ravi USA: Yeah, but coming to… like, I'm a bit focused on how to specify the… are there any best practices around giving the context? Like, we discussed about, like, the foreign case and all. Other than that, like, even the table column… I mean, different tables and different columns have its own domain-specific information and everything. Like, let's say we have a SAP database or a sales.
Krish NAik: Generally, for RAG, you have to keep those things in context.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, there are… how you will pass the data? There is no other way to know that the LA in LM will know that.
Ravi USA: Yeah, no, I'm talking about the text-to-SQL part, like, if a business user is.
Krish NAik: I'm talking about text-to-SQL only. I'm telling all those things that you are telling, you have to pass it in the context, otherwise how the LLM will…
Ravi USA: Okay, okay.
Ravi USA: Okay.
Krish NAik: You try it out.
Rahul USA: Can… can I hang one there?
Ravi USA: Yeah, one last thing, one last question. Like, I'm not sure if this is covered before. If so, like, it would be really helpful for me. Like, so these rack pipelines, like, when we are trying to do it in production, like, our database data sources are in such a way that, like, we will have updation of the sources of different.
Krish NAik: For that, you have to maintain a file version control system of your own. That is nothing related to AI.
Ravi USA: I mean, but still, we have to generate embeddings every time that we are, like, modifying the source.
Krish NAik: Who do you have to generate for a particular document?
Krish NAik: If you have the embeddings, if you feel that the document is not changed, you can save it as a cache, or somewhere else in your DB also means sometimes they put it in Postgres. That is another approach, but you have to always maintain, through a file hash.
Krish NAik: Okay, that any file got changed or not, you have to check the hashes. If anything got changed, then again, do a complete re-embedding approach, or you can check which part of the document that got updated. You have to do that particular differentiation, and based on that, that completely comes under file control.
Krish NAik: You need to have a FPS, that we call it, a file version system, just like GitHub.
Krish NAik: Where it tracks everything.
Ravi USA: Sure. This part is, I mean, is there any project where this, at least a basic version of this, is discussed, or can you at least provide some resources on, like, how we can engineer that kind of a design?
Krish NAik: Much more about engineering.
Ravi USA: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Krish NAik: So, like, really, the thing that you are asking, I have to look into that, because for me, in my own…
Krish NAik: projects that is there in mine, but I will look into something, because really, that part I have not gone through. We have to design that system by taking file hashes. I will look into that, because directly, I don't think in some cases, in some blogs also, I've not seen that.
Krish NAik: So, really, neither in papers they will be discussing about this engineering approach. I will look into it, because I don't think directly it will be available.
Krish NAik: Neither nobody teaches you that file control, because it's totally a simple engineering thing.
Krish NAik: Nothing related to AI, guys.
Ravi USA: Yeah, but one thing is sure, right? Like, whenever we delete some data documents, or whenever we update some documents, we have to generate the embeddings every time, once again, everything again, right?
Krish NAik: Yes. Re-embedding, or probably, if anything comes as a new. You keep it as a chart.
Ravi USA: Okay.
Krish NAik: junk.
Ravi USA: Fantastic.
Krish NAik: Okay, re-embedding the complete file is not necessary. If you feel only 3 lines got added, why you will do the complete re-embedding?
Krish NAik: You need to do only the embedding for that particular chunk that has been appended into the document.
Ravi USA: Okay, so we will be able to pinpoint the chunks that were, like, added, something like that, so using this, I mean, this approach?
Krish NAik: can, for example, for a certain document, there will be a certain link. This document has 20 charts. Later on, the document got updated. You saw, okay, 4 lines got added. Let's create a new chart. Done!
Ravi USA: Okay, okay, yeah. And deletions also can be done automatically, like, like, some text is deleted, so can we, like, delete this corresponding embedding.
Krish NAik: Now, then you have to check that, whether it's part of 2 chunk, 3-chunk, 4-chunk, then you have to delete those chunks where you have that specific piece of text.
Ravi USA: Okay, yeah.
Ravi USA: Sure, yeah. The, like, like I asked, like, that if you point us to the design, that would be really helpful, like, yeah, thank you.
Krish NAik: Alright, Robin.
Krish NAik: I got your point, but again, that's the thing.
Krish NAik: It's not related to, so nobody teaches that things.
Ravi USA: Yeah, yeah, definitely.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Next, I think, you were there in the panelist, you can let me know, Raul, what is the issue you are facing?
Rahul USA: So, Paul, I… I am… I think so I have configured everything correctly. Here are my…
Rahul USA: here are my, data. What I'm getting is, it's saying connection failed, you know? And if I go here…
Rahul USA: I have copied the connection from… from this site, so you said copy this.
Krish NAik: No, no, directly copy the string and keep it in one place, yes.
Rahul USA: Yeah, yeah.
Krish NAik: That's the only thing, not cool, because.
Rahul USA: Yeah.
Krish NAik: Okay, it's telling me the password… password you are sure? No, this is correct.
Rahul USA: Yeah, yeah, yeah, I just copied the generated default password, and I just…
Krish NAik: Then it should work. 5432… So, I'm also surprised that why it is not working, you know? Is it…
Rahul USA: Is it, like.
Krish NAik: Check the spaces. If there are extra spaces also in .env, then also it creates the issue.
Rahul USA: Extra spaces…
Krish NAik: Because I… because that part, only that character is equal to, and after that Postgres, after that, there is no…
Rahul USA: So that, the, the colon.
Krish NAik: Okay, no, no, no, host, why you have kept slash Postgres removed at, first of all. Slash Postgres removed.
Krish NAik: Remove the number also.
Krish NAik: Those things you were passing in the portal.
Rahul USA: Yeah, yeah, yeah, but with that also, it's…
Krish NAik: Okay, that also not working.
Rahul USA: Yeah, yeah, yeah, I just tested with that, too.
Krish NAik: Okay, do a control lesson, then try to do.
Krish NAik: Alright, so watch is studying postgrace.
Krish NAik: This one you have chased, okay, Subhash, I will add you, okay? So, help others, because really, I have not changed. And you can add your IP also, sometimes the IP blocks in that one. Subhash, raise your hand.
Krish NAik: So, boss, okay, I will… Add you to panelists, okay?
Krish NAik: Because of IP block. Generally, in other databases, also, you have to add your own IP. Because of that, it might decay.
Rahul USA: Interesting.
Krish NAik: IPv4, string, okay, alright, I will check on that one. Yeah, so Bash, I think you can, speak.
Subhash: Yeah, yeah, Paul. So I also face the same issue. So, I asked CharGPT what was the issue. It says, because of IP block, it is, it will happen sometimes.
Subhash: So, we need to go to Super Base and change the, method. Well, can you go to Super Base and change the method to, instead of direct connection, can you click on drop-down?
Subhash: the method.
Rahul USA: decide.
Subhash: No, no, no.
Subhash: Go back to click…
Krish NAik: on Connect.
Subhash: Connect.
Rahul USA: Click on gas.
Krish NAik: That direct connection dropout, drop-down is there. Just click on that, direct connection, yes.
Subhash: Yeah, transaction pooler. Select transaction pooler. Yeah, you can copy this and… A patient, debatable.
Krish NAik: Yes, same with the subject. Others also just try. If direct connection is not working, use…
Krish NAik: The pooled one-session pooling.
Rahul USA: Oh, this one, right? Okay.
Rahul USA: So you want me to use this one, correct?
Krish NAik: Current.
Krish NAik: Comment this one, yes.
Rahul USA: Superbase.com, yeah. What I'm doing wrong here, again?
Subhash: No, the total, the variables were also different.
Subhash: Then let me paste once again.
Rahul USA: So should I just copy the entire…
Krish NAik: Check the port whether it is changed or not. Just bring that. Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, okay.
Krish NAik: If… The rest, I think it will be the same.
Krish NAik: You can click on the view parameter also, yes.
Rahul USA: strange.
Rahul USA: Oh, jeez.
Krish NAik: Generally?
Krish NAik: So, I have not faced such issues a lot in my configuration.
Krish NAik: But yes, so inside your connection… Hmm, look.
Rahul USA: Polar Super Base, yeah.
Rahul USA: Oh, interesting.
Krish NAik: Because, that.
Subhash: Username… username is also different.
Rahul USA: Oh.
Krish NAik: check that.
Subhash: Yeah, I just, kept the…
Rahul USA: So.
Subhash: Actual things.
Rahul USA: So this is the… this is the host name.
Subhash: Yeah, yeah, username is also there.
Rahul USA: database, oh, this is the user O.
Subhash: Yeah.
Rahul USA: Okay, okay, okay, okay, thank you for that. Okay.
Rahul USA: So, now… This is interesting.
Krish NAik: You can directly look into that view parameters, it's much easier to understand.
Rahul USA: Yeah, I… I just copied the view parameter from here.
Krish NAik: That'll be fine.
Rahul USA: And paste it here, just to compare.
Rahul USA: No.
Rahul USA: This is the post, this is the port.
Rahul USA: This is the database. This is the user.
Rahul USA: Oh, you… Well…
Rahul USA: Do we have to give the poor a pull… pull mode transaction here, which is not there?
Subhash: Not required. No, not required.
Rahul USA: For you, it is working.
Subhash: Yeah, for me, it worked.
Subhash: I closed the IDEA, and I have opened again.
Subhash: Maybe sometimes ENV variables are not loading.
Rahul USA: Okay, so let me deactivate and try it again.
Krish NAik: It's restarting or no.
Rahul USA: Restart the kernel.
Krish NAik: Yes, if you're working with the notebook, I think you can do the restart of the kernel also. Okay, because right now, I think you are executing the script. In script, there is no such issues, because the script will be reloaded again.
Krish NAik: Just be… check with the port also.
Rahul USA: Okay, interesting. That's just… yeah, that's what I was wondering, okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, sampler than others.
Krish NAik: For everybody, it's working. Previous, it was not working, so I… So, please do the configuration for tomorrow also, okay? Everything is shared with you, just be sure you create another project, and then you can create.
Rahul USA: Let me close, and let me, come back, Paul, okay? Let me try to close IT, and then come back.
Krish NAik: Yes, sometimes, Fatamesh, you need to change some prompts.
Krish NAik: Okay, some things with respect to the similar quantit can be hard-coded.
Krish NAik: Alright, yes, you can… okay, let me go to others also.
Krish NAik: Let's go, whip in… U2317, Rajat…
Krish NAik: Okay, few people I have unmuted. Punam…
Vipin Tiwari: Hey, Paul, I'm getting one error, this,
Vipin Tiwari: No module named PSYCOPG2, not found.
Krish NAik: Just install the package and see, during installation, are you getting any error? Because that is the driver, that is the main Postgres SQL driver.
Vipin Tiwari: It's saying already installed.
Krish NAik: Sometimes check, that package creates sometimes an issue, that's why you can always have that checked. No module form? Please, it has two things. One is hyphen binary, the other one is without binary. So, according to your system, you have to check which one works for you.
Vipin Tiwari: For Windows, which one do you have to use?
Krish NAik: In Windows, also, binary works.
Krish NAik: Okay, because for others, also, it's working, I know Windows, it works.
Vipin Tiwari: In code, right, in connection string, binary is not mentioned. Do we need to mention binary there?
Krish NAik: Okay, just check whether the binary is working for you or not.
Krish NAik: just do a little bit of search, web search, or chat GPT, and just ask, like, according to your system configuration.
Rajat Khanna: one?
Krish NAik: Amos delivers Pinecone, we already created an API key in the… in my case, yes, you can use the same one. There is no restriction. You just need the API key from Pinecone, and nothing.
Rajat Khanna: Hi, Paul, I have one scenario-based question.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so the scenario, so it's like, in a, in a project, like, we are using,
Rajat Khanna: database. So, for example, Oracle SQL we are using, in which we are storing all the product and bundle-related information. So the same process as text2SQL, can be implemented on that. For example, like, we have created a chatbot, and we are just type, give me information about this product, or give me information about this bundle. So, we are just providing the product name or the bundle name, and the
Rajat Khanna: LLM will give us all the information based on directly fetching the data from the SQL.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so means this, Text2SQL will work, on that solution.
Krish NAik: Yes, texture SQL will work, but it will not work.
Rajat Khanna: No, no, so…
Krish NAik: issue.
Krish NAik: The context that you are passing, that is the most important thing. Context with relationship, whatever the thing that you've defined, you can pass it.
Rajat Khanna: No, yeah, so, the scenario is, like, we already have… it's a hypothetical scenario that I am building, while if we give… I give an interview, so there should be, which project I have worked on, and all those things. So the scenario base will be, like, I already have a,
Krish NAik: web application, and in that web application, we are fetching the information related to a product, bundle, and all those regions related. Yes, yes, you can perform using text-to-SQL. There is nothing to worry about.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, that's my only question, thank you.
E2317: Hi, Paul, Paul, this is Suhan's side.
Krish NAik: Yes, former others, Rahul, is it solved for you?
Rahul USA: Is it,
Rahul USA: It is, it is solved, the connections is solved. I missed the next, next part. Do you want me to just…
Rahul USA: run the… the create sample tables after running that as SQL, right?
Krish NAik: first of all, create the schema in that table editor, execute that query, sorry, not in the table editor, SQL editor. Just execute that part, the schema that I have shared. Okay.
Rahul USA: So, just, just, yeah, so the schema is created. Now, I have the schema here in the table.
Krish NAik: now you can generate. If you have the three tables ready, empty tables, then you can run that script.
Rahul USA: Run the create table, right?
Krish NAik: That's the only thing.
Krish NAik: Done.
Rahul USA: Okay, sounds good, thank you.
Krish NAik: One day tomorrow.
E2317: April,
Krish NAik: Yes.
E2317: Section 1. The first, when Texas,
E2317: text-to-squill, right? I was able to generate the tables and the schema, right? Schema and the generate both got generated. For the second, project, which we will be doing tomorrow, right?
E2317: I tried…
E2317: I just clone… I just set up the environment, right? And under the data folder, you have generate SampleData.py.
Krish NAik: Correct?
E2317: I installed the Faker package and the another package which you mentioned.
Krish NAik: I don't.
E2317: I'm… I… so I installed both of them, now it's working fine, but whenever I'm doing Python and then data slash…
E2317: generate sample.py, right? It is saying that, the database URL is… make sure the database URL is correct in your .env file.
Krish NAik: just keep the .env file in that folder only, wherever, because it.
E2317: Yeah, absolutely, yes.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, bring out that file from here. If it doesn't detect at .env, then only it will create a problem.
E2317: So, shall I restart and then start again? I think if it's… Or…
Krish NAik: just remove the file. Just be sure in which, wherever is your script, there only is your .env file.
Krish NAik: Same folder. That's the only thing.
E2317: Oh, same folder, right?
Krish NAik: I just…
E2317: medical record.
Krish NAik: Not fine.
Krish NAik: Next.
Krish NAik: Melind?
Krish NAik: Sampat Amar.
Amarsrinivas: Marie.
Krish NAik: Yes, I'm already.
Amarsrinivas: Yeah, actually, I just want to request you, is there a possibility to, add one topic, especially, or session, to cover AWS, Athena, S3 query, and, or Redshift tables, and then generating, replicating the same, LLM,
Amarsrinivas: the same tables instead of SQL, so that it will be helpful for us.
Krish NAik: It's the same thing.
Amarsrinivas: Because it works on the Parquet files right there.
Krish NAik: Yes, Parquet file, that is fine, there is no issue. See, you can connect it with any database, get your data, create your own custom workflow. That only I showed in Notebook 3, no?
Amarsrinivas: Yeah, mainly Parquet files are connecting to AWS, is there a boilerplate, available so that we can…
Krish NAik: There is no such direct violin plate, like, see, I have to even create the content. It's not like that directly everything, even I will look into the AWS documentation, and then only I will do it. Okay. But I know, if… see, if it is possible in one, it will be possible in any other.
Amarsrinivas: Yeah, I agree 100%. I thought, many people has done, if there is any reference link, I thought you know. That's why…
Krish NAik: Direct reference link, I don't have, because this time I'm using Superbase probably as C. That's why… because this time I thought SuperBase was easy to get connected.
Krish NAik: later on, in AWS Infra, okay, I will pick that one, because one project, I'm planning that you guys will be doing, okay, in there, I will keep it, that specific requirement.
Amarsrinivas: Sure, sure. Thanks, thanks for… thank you.
Krish NAik: Thank you.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah, hi, Bonn.
Krish NAik: Yes.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah, how to create the schema in this, Superbase, so that's better.
Krish NAik: How to create the schema? What do you mean by create the schema?
samapth reddy vummanthala: Obviously.
Krish NAik: You have to execute the schema that I have provided. So whenever you are creating any database, that is the first thing, you decide the schema, no?
Krish NAik: That is nothing related to superbase, it's simple SQL concept.
samapth reddy vummanthala: So, you want me to run in this, VSQ?
Krish NAik: SQL editor. Yes, SQL editor, you have to just execute that query, and based on that, your tables will be created. And later on, I am just populating those tables from my custom data through the script.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah.
samapth reddy vummanthala: And one more thing, so up to now, I faced the connection issue, so that is solved with the help of this connection pooler and all.
samapth reddy vummanthala: But when I run the load environment in our Postgres, Jupyter notebook, it is taking old one, I mean, it's,
samapth reddy vummanthala: And…
Krish NAik: If it's taking older one, you could just do a restart.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah, it's impossible.
Krish NAik: Then restart the console, and then try to exit.
Krish NAik: Alright… Next, Melind, Kiran, Rohit, Naga… okay, Kiran?
Krish NAik: Yes, Kiran, no response from Kiran. Milind?
Kiran Rathod: No, I hype book.
Krish NAik: Okay, get understood.
Kiran Rathod: Paul, actually, I was trying to connect to the Super Base,
Kiran Rathod: Through the code, and I can see the.
Krish NAik: Yes, Pratamesh, every time it will go, because prompt catching feature is not available in OpenAI when very few LLMs it is available. Very specifically with respect to Haiku, Anthropic model supports prompt catching, okay, but others doesn't support, so nothing that we can do. If you are using it with OpenAI, every time it will be synced.
Krish NAik: Yes, definitely.
Naga: Sure, Paul.
Krish NAik: First kid, I'm…
Kiran Rathod: Paul, I want to share my screen, because when I tried to.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Kiran Rathod: run test connection, right? I am getting address of failure, could not translate host name.
Krish NAik: Aruna, it is in the Advanced RAT tutorial GitHub. Please check that, Aruna. Yes, Naga, tell.
Naga: Yeah, I want to… I actually am able to, create and all that, like, the connection, everything happening, but the data is not inserted.
Naga: I ran the last notebook.
Krish NAik: Share your screen, share your screen. First of all, let me look into Rohit in the meantime.
Kiran Rathod: Paul, I, think I have shared my screen.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine, you were sharing? Okay, just tell…
Kiran Rathod: Can't see, yeah, I can see this host translation error.
Krish NAik: dot ENV, where is your .envy? First of all, show me in the price.
Kiran Rathod: dot ENV is…
Krish NAik: Alright.env is here, db, okay, this one is coming. Otherwise, change that session playing, what Sua suggested. Do the other way around, what you should.
Krish NAik: Try that part.
Krish NAik: The direct connection is not working, take the pool one.
Kiran Rathod: Poodle one.
Krish NAik: Right now, Subhash told. Even, I think, Rahul did it, it worked for him.
Naga: Yeah, it works for me, so I'll just show…
Krish NAik: When you clicked on connect, from their drop-down, you'll be getting that particular option.
Kiran Rathod: Yeah, I have this direct connection, and a shared pooler I need to…
Krish NAik: You cannot see that particular screen, but you have to pass, because the environment variables, that needs to be connected correctly.
Naga: Yeah, it needs to be like this, like, if you go to the pool connection, you'll get…
Naga: Similar to this.
Krish NAik: Because check the port, 6543A.
Naga: 6543, yeah.
Kiran Rathod: But here, for me, it is 5432 is.
Krish NAik: No, that removed… portcrest.user, okay?
Krish NAik: Is that user coming in your params? Have a check on the main entities. If it is there, I think that will be the one.
Naga: You should take that transaction pool, then the transaction pool, then copy those config, like, variables, like, post…
Kiran Rathod: It is not this direct connection, I need to go to Transaction Pooler and take.
Naga: You should go to Transaction Polar and get those also.
Kiran Rathod: Got it, let me try that, thanks. I'll stop my screen share.
Naga: No.
Naga: So, Paul…
Krish NAik: I don't know.
Naga: So I ran the… this one, it found all the four tables, and then I ran the fourth notebook, which is this, right?
Krish NAik: That's correct.
Naga: And there is some insert statements in this, and I see… but I don't see any data weight inserted in the database.
Krish NAik: That's the same database I am using, no? It's not a different database, now only you inserted the data.
Naga: I… yeah, I inserted the data, but, like, it's not coming up in the… This, backbone here.
Krish NAik: Here, nothing will come.
Naga: They get up.
Krish NAik: Morning welcome.
Naga: Here, this is a visualizer tool.
Krish NAik: just to tell you that ID connection, if you have multiple relationships, here it's nothing related to that.
Krish NAik: One is nuclear tables.
Krish NAik: What do you want to look? What is…
Naga: I want to… where is the data? Like, I think you… you were showing the data…
Krish NAik: Not in the table, no. Go to the table editor.
Krish NAik: Go to the table editor, there you will see the data.
Krish NAik: In the left-hand side, second option, in the… below whom, table editor.
Krish NAik: Here you have the data, click on Products.
Naga: Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, because right now this is empty. Probably you have not done the insertion of the data. You have to do the insertion.
Naga: The fourth notebook only, right? I mean, that was… this was the note… this is the notebook to…
Krish NAik: Before executing the fourth notebook, you have to push the data there, no?
Naga: Yeah, but how to push the data?
Krish NAik: I have shared the script, no sample, this one. Where is that sample, this createsampleTables.py. You have to execute that file.
Naga: Create some folder.
Naga: Well, it's unbrooked as God.
Krish NAik: I know it, but I…
Rohit Srivastava: Hi there. Thanks, Jenny?
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, your volume is a bit low today at the sound.
Rohit Srivastava: Excuse me.
Rohit Srivastava: Please, fees.
Krish NAik: Yes, Naga. Now the data is available, just do a refresh, you will see the data. Yes.
Rohit Srivastava: Can you hear me now?
Krish NAik: Yes.
Rohit Srivastava: Alright, great. Alright. So, first, let me share my screen. I'm facing challenges with the connection itself, the first thing.
Krish NAik: First one.
Rohit Srivastava: Yep.
Krish NAik: Data is populated now. Now you can actually run that and you can test it, okay?
Naga: Boom.
Rohit Srivastava: Alright.
Rohit Srivastava: Let me share my screen first.
Krish NAik: Yes, Prathamish, it will be executing. So, generally, the schema will be very big. It will be majorly 100,000 characters.
Rohit Srivastava: Hey, so Rangshu, I mean, this is what the details I've gotten, and if you look at my…
Rohit Srivastava: Just give me a second, let me pull up… where is it? Yeah.
Rohit Srivastava: So this is how it is.
Krish NAik: Hmm, select for a URI, only take the first, don't change hearing.
Rohit Srivastava: Okay, you alright, alright.
Krish NAik: Now, this one you have taken, the user other one, direct connection, drop-down is there.
Rohit Srivastava: Okay, from here, use, Transaction Pooler.
Rohit Srivastava: Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can see view parameters, you can copy this entire thing, copy and clickbot, and you can also look into that view parameters.
Krish NAik: Now, if that is not working, direct connection pooling, sometimes they block the IP.
Rohit Srivastava: So they say host, and then.
Krish NAik: Oh, yeah, yeah.
Rohit Srivastava: Alright, so… so, wait a minute, just first let me copy this, and then get me back to this,
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah.
Rohit Srivastava: So… so this host will change, is it?
Krish NAik: Yes, that will change, port will change.
Rohit Srivastava: Okay…
Rohit Srivastava: Port will change, alright. User…
Krish NAik: it overwrite the previous, customer product tables? Yes, Fuham, you have to create it in a different project.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you use it in the same one, okay, because there, I think the schema will be different, in the other one, the schema will be different. So it's better you create a separate project for that.
Naga: If I have to address this question.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, there is no pull mode, params here.
Rohit Srivastava: Okay, that's fine.
Rohit Srivastava: So, password is fine, right? Password will remain the same.
Krish NAik: with the same only.
Rohit Srivastava: Alright, okay. So, just let me do…
Naga: Come in.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, I can hear you.
Naga: Okay, so I want to test this, so…
Naga: Should I test on the, like, another cell, or where do I test this?
Krish NAik: Yes, create a new cell if you want to do any testing.
Naga: Yeah, that's… I see, create engine, I'm asking the question, but every time it's giving the same answer, I gotta see, like, a query engine query, how many customers are there? It's supposed to give me the customer numbers, right?
Krish NAik: The go below that, it will give you the number also.
Krish NAik: If it's telling Simply…
Naga: Oh, okay, there are 500, okay, okay.
Rohit Srivastava: It's still giving me error, you see?
Krish NAik: Because that's the only thing. Because, what error it's telling, okay, connection failed, AWS pooler…
Krish NAik: 6543, alright, password, only those two are the params that need to be, I think.
Rohit Srivastava: Password authentication failed. I mean, I wonder if my password is wrong. No, I don't think so. But still, let me look at that.
Krish NAik: Just created quickly another, project. Another project.
Rohit Srivastava: project, okay, fine.
Rohit Srivastava: Let me do one thing.
Rohit Srivastava: Hmm…
Krish NAik: Go to that.org, the first option, where it's written.
Rohit Srivastava: Alright, alright.
Krish NAik: Where you can create a new project.
Rohit Srivastava: New project, alright, let me name it this time.
Rohit Srivastava: Artist.
Rohit Srivastava: Okay, database, password… Suggest a strong password, alright, now we'll copy this.
Rohit Srivastava: Use strong password.
Rohit Srivastava: Copy, alright. Password is copied. Now, creating a new pass… new project, alright.
Rohit Srivastava: Hmm.
Rohit Srivastava: There we go.
Krish NAik: Let's click on connect the same way.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, same thing, right?
Krish NAik: direct connection, change it if it doesn't work for you. For me, direct connection was working, otherwise use…
Rohit Srivastava: No, let me… let me give it a try with direct connection. No, but, with the problem… the challenge is direct connection, this IP is not getting resolved.
Krish NAik: Yeah, okay, alright, fine, then use the other one only.
Rohit Srivastava: Transaction pooler, alright.
Rohit Srivastava: The password happens to be now…
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah.
Rohit Srivastava: This is the password now.
Rohit Srivastava: Right, so let me put it in quotes.
Rohit Srivastava: Just the weather.
Krish NAik: And raised melind Muntasar, yes.
Rohit Srivastava: Hmm… It'd be…
Mudassar Hakim: Hey, Paul, in the meantime, Roeth is sharing his screen. I just have a question here. So, I'm just wondering, this, X2SQL, right? Typically today, if this activity needs to be done, there are tools like Power BI and, you know, other tools…
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, BI tools are there.
Mudassar Hakim: So I'm just trying to, you know, figure out if what is the production value of this capability today. Under what circumstances would I… because, I mean, if I had come down to evaluate that, okay, maybe I'm saving a developer's salary versus, you know, hitting the OpenAI models, and getting the work done, I was just thinking from a
Mudassar Hakim: practicality perspective, right? How much practical it is to move this capability, even if, let's assume, this gives me perfect answers every time.
Mudassar Hakim: From that, query output perspective.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Rohit Srivastava: Shall I… shall I suggest you something?
Rohit Srivastava: Modesta? Who is this?
Rohit Srivastava: Muda said, a few days ago, there was a very interesting debate between Arnav Goswami and AI.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, see that, yeah.
Rohit Srivastava: Did you watch it?
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, yeah, we've all seen it, yeah.
Rohit Srivastava: So that, I think, Delivers the answer.
Mudassar Hakim: No, no, no, it doesn't. That is just for a fancy thing.
Rohit Srivastava: Definitely.
Krish NAik: click on this.
Rohit Srivastava: It's very realistic. It's very realistic. All you have to see is the… all you have.
Mudassar Hakim: to understand the costing aspect over here, right? 5.
Mudassar Hakim: that is all nice and good, but when we are trying to propose this or get something established in a enterprise production environment, I think we need to look at all the corners, right? Yeah, Paul, you're saying?
Krish NAik: My main purpose was to generate
Krish NAik: the query. You have to understand.
Krish NAik: other tools are there. They won't be generating… see, right now, the idea was
Krish NAik: through a natural language, I'm generating the query. That is the main thing.
Krish NAik: In BI tools and others, okay, you cannot do that particular generation.
milind kulkarni: You need a tool or something like that, and generally, BI tools, again.
Krish NAik: that comes with a cost and other things. Here, also, you have at least lesser cost as compared to a BI tool. BI licenses, whether I'm talking about ClickView, Tableau, Power BI, they are pretty much very, very expensive.
Krish NAik: I feel that, generally, if you have lesser tables than others, try to take this approach. Okay, less amount of data, but really, if it's in billions and trillions of rows, they can, again, test to SQL, really.
Krish NAik: As per the research papers and academic papers it has been shown, it really doesn't work that good when it actually scales up.
Mudassar Hakim: For that matter, one also?
Krish NAik: For one years.
Mudassar Hakim: No, no, one hour, one hour, one hour at AI, which we are going to see tomorrow.
Krish NAik: No, VANA.ai, it actually helps you. There are some other features, like in VANA, you can actually train on top of your data. Few other features are there in VANA. So, VANA is actually used in production.
Krish NAik: FANA is a lot of features only for one thing. Their main productive text is equal. You have to understand.
Krish NAik: So they have optimized it in next level, in Lang Channel, Lama Index, those things are notable.
Rohit Srivastava: Okay. So…
Krish NAik: One is directly plug, play, you bring your data, you can train your data, okay, after training, you can build a rag on top of that, so really, in a lot of things, it actually helps.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay, I'll let Rajiv… Rohit, Rajiv… I'll take my query a little later. Yeah, go ahead, Rohit.
Rohit Srivastava: Thank you, thank you, Modesta. Sorangshu, I mean, I did copied and I configured all that. If you see, these are the host settings and all.
Rohit Srivastava: Database postgate, user this.
Krish NAik: You don't need, actually, quotes. Simply, without the quotes, it should work. Why you are passing the quotes?
Rohit Srivastava: Just to ensure that nothing goes wrong.
Krish NAik: Because the quotes are fine, sometimes we use it in ENV, otherwise…
Rohit Srivastava: Okay, fine, I'll remove the quotes.
Krish NAik: Because resting Postgres… Because, again, the user that is coming…
Krish NAik: In the default Ariat connection, directly, I use it.
Krish NAik: With that one, okay.
Krish NAik: Now, you can check out the session cooler also, because so many options are there.
Rohit Srivastava: Alright, session pooler, okay.
Krish NAik: tested, because really, because this is a… Place.
Krish NAik: With session puller, the… probably, like, what is the port number? Again, in the view parameters, you can look into the user.
Rohit Srivastava: Let's see, let's see, pool mode. But then, do I need to change the pool mode also here, somewhere? Yeah, here it is, pool mode, transaction, pool in…
Krish NAik: Okay, because if direct connection is not working, go with transactional. If it is not working, then finally go with session puller.
Krish NAik: For IP, in your case, also, it will be IPv4, so try to check the session puller button.
Krish NAik: And session puller, the port will be 5432.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, so… I think… wait a minute,
Rohit Srivastava: Pooler.subase, yeah, this is correct, this user is correct, pool mode session.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah.
Rohit Srivastava: Focal… 3, 2… Oops.
Rohit Srivastava: 5432… Right, and that was, I guess, the only thing that needs to be changed, or…
Rohit Srivastava: Take them out.
Krish NAik: param there, no, check the params. Don't ask me, check the param there. I feel that.
Rohit Srivastava: I do.
Krish NAik: It's justified.
Rohit Srivastava: Adams.
Krish NAik: Correct, AWS, user is there, database, Postgres, okay, alright. Fine. Check. Execute the script and check whether it's working.
Rohit Srivastava: Oh, okay.
milind kulkarni: Pearl kindergart?
Krish NAik: Yes, millionth, millionth, millionth, cool.
milind kulkarni: I'm only checking… I'm looking how do I run that, get, generate SQL, because when I'm trying to run it, I get a database URL not formed. Do I need to set up some other URL?
milind kulkarni: For that as in ENV file.
Krish NAik: generate, which one you are telling Milind?
Krish NAik: Generally?
milind kulkarni: So, I… from the today's code, I ran the create sample table and sample table. It all worked fine.
milind kulkarni: But then our… later on, you were showing that another, GitHub link, right? Multi… multi…
Krish NAik: Yeah, multilater than that one, yes.
milind kulkarni: Right, so I could create the schema, but when I'm trying to run the generate sample data, it gives me error.
milind kulkarni: Database URL is needed.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so you have to keep it in the same, just be sure it is in the same place, the information from which folder.
milind kulkarni: my copied IPO, do I clone that whole repo?
Krish NAik: Why you need… you don't need to clone the repo, just get the script, and just be sure you have the…
milind kulkarni: what I did. I got the script, I copied into the same text-to-SQL rack today's, this one, but in my ENV file, there is no database underscore U already, right?
Krish NAik: No, no, you have to keep… see, generally, I think in that case, I have given you the direct DB string. In there, the approach is a little bit different.
Krish NAik: That's why. It's not the same one, you can use the same approach that you have done today, but there, I think it will be different. If you look into the test connection file also, there the script is different, because directly I've used that DB connection string rather than breaking it into multiple parts.
milind kulkarni: Yeah, so, so should I… should I create a new environment code variable called databaseURL and put that DB connection?
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, yes, yes, try to.
milind kulkarni: Okay. Okay, thank you.
Krish NAik: Thank you.
milind kulkarni: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, well, then Soham, can you abate your hand?
E2317: football,
E2317: Paulie, can you just narrate me the steps for the new project? So, what I've done is I've cloned that project.
E2317: And in that project, I've created a new…
E2317: a new project in the ProScale account also.
Krish NAik: Alright.
E2317: What I've done is, I have just run that Python command, so it is able to now… it is… it is saying in the terminal, connected successfully, right? But there.
Krish NAik: Yes.
E2317: Then there's another print statement, generating customers. So it is showing… I'll just… I'm not able to share screen, it's locked from my system.
Krish NAik: Real good.
Krish NAik: Probably I will re-vary this.
E2317: Thank you.
Krish NAik: done the verification, but I feel that it should work.
E2317: I don't have an access to… Share my screen.
Krish NAik: You don't have… you are in the panelist, so you can.
E2317: Right now, my office laptop is…
Krish NAik: Okay, hmm.
E2317: But I've shared my… Comment.
Krish NAik: The… I don't know…
Krish NAik: which is telling remove with codes, that's why I don't use quotes, actually.
E2317: So, from line 1, it is giving this error.
Krish NAik: Alright, I will check the script whether it's working or not, okay?
Krish NAik: Because later on then tomorrow… If I feel that the script should be fine, previously I've tested it and done it, but again, I will have a check that. Okay. If there is something wrong with the script, for sure we'll be getting an error.
Krish NAik: I will check up then tomorrow, quickly, it's a 2-minute thing only, so most of you have figured out most of the things.
Krish NAik: In today's class, so in tomorrow's class, the same thing that we'll be doing, little with VANA, and then finally we'll start with the project part.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so I think, for today, I'm done, okay? Then…
Krish NAik: Jamie asks you how to create the schema.
Krish NAik: You have to decide, no, like, how you want your tables to be done.
Krish NAik: That totally depends upon the logic, based on how your data will be there.
Krish NAik: There is no way, so whenever in SQL, you have to decide what is the schema, nobody creates for it.
Krish NAik: You have to plan what will be the entries, what will be the fields based on that.
Krish NAik: You can keep it around 536, so…
Krish NAik: Oh, alright guys, so I'll be concluding the session then. Let's meet tomorrow, okay? Can I do the practical pull-up? I'm going to be using, nothing for a pull-up.
Krish NAik: Collab is for beginners. Right now, we are into project making.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so let's meet tomorrow and continue our discussion. So, bye-bye everyone, thanks for joining.